Welcome back, everyone.
欢迎大家回来。
Next we have session two on ICN for
接下来我们将进行第二场关于ICN的会议
wireless edge networking chaired by Eve Schooler from Intel.
由英特尔的Eve Schooler主持的无线边缘网络会议。
Eve, go ahead.
伊芙，请开始吧。
>> Well, we've got three great presentations today.
好的，今天我们有三场精彩的演讲。
We're gonna lead off with one on the topic of ICN when a program overview,
我们将首先介绍一个关于ICN的主题，当做一个项目概览。
by Dr. Shree Katyayani Tsikata Suara, otherwise known as Katyayani.
由Shree Katyayani Tsikata Suara博士主持，她也被称为Katyayani。
Who's a senior research scientist at Intel labs,
谁是英特尔实验室的高级研究科学家，
leading research in information centric networks for edge computing.
领先的研究专注于边缘计算的信息中心网络。
And her research focuses on applications where ICN can add value to industry.
她的研究重点是ICN能为行业增加价值的应用领域。
Katyayani is the Intel PI for the joint Intel-NSF ICN-WEN Center.
Katyayani是英特尔与美国国家科学基金会合作的ICN-WEN中心的英特尔PI（主要研究员）。
Take it away Katyayani >> Thank you so much Eve,
Eve，非常感谢你。
I'm starting to share my brain here.
我开始在这里分享我的想法了。
Okay, so I'll be just giving a brief overview of
好的，所以我将简要概述一下
the joint Intel-NSF ICN-WEN Center.
联合英特尔-美国国家科学基金会ICN-WEN中心。
It actually successfully recently completed its three year tenure.
它实际上最近成功地完成了它的三年任期。
And we have two other great professors talking about it, but
我们还有两位出色的教授将对此进行讨论，但是
I just wanna give a brief overview.
我只是想简要概述一下。
So the idea, when we set up this joint center with NSF.
所以当我们与美国国家科学基金会（NSF）一起建立这个联合中心时的想法是。
The idea was to explore what are some of the potential of ICN especially
我们建立这个联合中心时的想法是探索信息中心网络（ICN）尤其是在未来可能的潜力。
over wireless edge networks in view of 5G and
在5G视角下的无线边缘网络上
5G+ or the new evolution of networks.
5G+ 或网络的新演进。
And also when we have lot many more devices and data at the edges,
而且当我们在边缘拥有更多的设备和数据时，
we wanted to see what kind of potential does ICN have.
我们想要了解ICN有什么样的潜力。
What kind of solutions can it provide to meet some of the more strict requirements?
它能提供哪些解决方案来满足一些更严格的要求？
Whether it's latency, bandwidth, and so on.
无论是延迟、带宽等等。
And we also wanted to look at more realistic deployments or applications
我们还想研究更现实的部署或应用情况。
typically used at the edges, whether it's AR VR, autonomous driving, and so on.
通常用于边缘计算，无论是增强现实虚拟现实、自动驾驶等等。
And another important aspect of the center was
另一个重要方面的中心是
that we wanted to look at three pillars simultaneously.
我们希望同时关注三大支柱。
That is, the wireless device endpoints,
即无线设备端点，
the network infrastructure and security and privacy.
网络基础设施以及安全与隐私。
So we wanted security to be part of the story,
所以我们希望安全成为故事的一部分，
part of the solution and not an afterthought.
所以我们希望安全成为解决方案的一部分，而不是事后才想起的事情。
And I believe that the teams actually did a great job doing that.
我相信那些团队确实在这方面做得很好。
And we had three main projects as part of this center.
我们这个中心主要有三个项目。
The first few that I've listed here ISAR,
我们这个中心主要有三个项目。ISAR是首先我在这里列出的几个项目之一，
the hotbed UCLA and SPLICE with the hobbit timer.
我们这个中心主要有三个项目。ISAR是首先我在这里列出的几个项目之一，他们使用了NDN和教授Jeff Burke和热床UCLA以及与霍比特计时器的SPLICE项目。
They used NDN and the professors, Jeff Burke and
他们使用了NDN和教授Jeff Burke以及
Trina Chakotay will be talking about it.
Trina Chakotay 将会讲述这个话题。
And I'll let them give you all the wonderful details.
我会让他们给你讲述所有精彩的细节。
The third line LSN used, it did not use NDN and use mumble at first.
第三行LSN使用的时候，它最初没有使用NDN，而是使用了mumble。
And of course there were a total of ten universities in the whole effort.
当然，在整个努力中共有十所大学参与。
And we also had a great advisory team that we put together.
我们还组建了一个非常棒的顾问团队。
We had a board of advisors, Geng Wu, who I believe will be talking later today.
我们还组建了一个顾问团队，我相信今天晚些时候会有耿武发言。
And of course Eve Schooler that you all know, and also Udayan Mukherjee.
当然，你们都认识的Eve Schooler，还有Udayan Mukherjee也在其中。
And we also had a couple of external advisors, Dave Oran and
我们还有几位外部顾问，包括Dave Oran和Christian Tschudin。
Christian Tschudin.
克里斯蒂安·楚丁。
And all of them provided great feedback
他们都提供了极好的反馈。
guidance during this whole three years.
在这整整三年里的指导。
We also had a lot of support from NSF.
我们也得到了来自国家科学基金会的大量支持。
Darleen Fisher, Monisha Ghosh Thyaga had started it off.
Darleen Fisher、Monisha Ghosh和Thyaga一起开始了这个项目。
And also we had a good support system with an Intel management team,
我们还得到了英特尔管理团队的大力支持，
and also multiple Intel champions who would attend the, we had monthly calls.
我们还有多位英特尔的支持者会参加我们的每月电话会议。
We had annual workshops and also semiannual sort of virtual workshop.
我们举办了年度研讨会，也有每半年一次的虚拟研讨会。
And it was great interacting with the team.
与团队互动真的很棒。
At least I personally learned so much from the center and from the interactions.
至少我个人从中心和互动中学到了很多。
And in the last slide,
在最后一张幻灯片中，
what I wanted to mention was a little bit about our own learnings.
我想提一下的是关于我们自己的学习心得。
I know the professors talking right after we'll be going over all the technical
我知道紧接着我们讨论的教授们将会回顾所有的技术细节以及他们在整个项目中积累的学习心得。
details and learnings that they gathered throughout the projects.
细节以及他们在整个项目中积累的学习心得。
But I thought it might be more useful if I talked about some of our own learnings
但我认为如果我谈论一些我们自己的学习心得可能会更有帮助。
as Intel as a research lab.
作为一个英特尔的研究实验室。
When we try to go and take these ICN solutions and
当我们尝试去采纳这些ICN解决方案并将其融入到行业解决方案中时。
incorporate them into industry solutions.
将它们融入到行业解决方案中。
And I thought that might be something useful for everyone to hear.
我认为这可能是每个人都会觉得有用的信息。
So, one of the first things we learned is,
所以，我们学到的第一件事之一是，
when you talk to somebody in the business unit at Intel or
当你在英特尔与业务部门的某人交谈时，
anywhere else in the industry.
在行业的其他任何地方。
The first thing that you'll see is they compare ICN to existing systems and
首先你会注意到的是，他们将ICN与现有系统进行了比较，
not just TCP-IP or TCP-IP with enhancements.
不仅仅是TCP-IP或者带有增强功能的TCP-IP。
So if you say, I have a great solution for caching or video distribution.
所以如果你说，我有一个很棒的缓存或视频分发解决方案。
They'll say, okay, this is the latest and greatest CDN that I have.
他们会说，好的，这是我拥有的最新最先进的CDN。
And not only just the CDN now, CDNs are coming into the carrier networks and
而且现在不仅仅是CDN，CDN正在进入运营商网络并且
putting them on the base station, okay?
将它们放置在基站上，好吗？
How does it compare to that?
它与那个相比如何？
So that is a gap I felt that was there in some of the typical
所以那是我感觉在一些典型的情况下存在的差距。
academic evaluations and how industry looks at it.
学术评价以及产业界的看法。
And also a lot of times it's better at least when we are looking at
以及在我们观察时，很多时候至少会更好。
solutions where ICN can provide the biggest benefits.
解决方案在哪里，ICN能提供最大的好处。
It's where to go for
解决方案在哪里，
a place where there is no real solution then offer just a better solution.
在没有真正解决方案的地方，那就提供一个更好的解决方案。
So that there is an area there is no real solution industry is actually struggling
所以在那些没有真正解决方案的领域，行业实际上是在挣扎。
with it, and then you say here I have the solution.
因此，当你这样做，并且说我这里有解决方案时。
But when you do that, the other thing,
但是当你那样做时，另一件事情是，
the question we get asked is, how does it then integrate with existing systems?
我们经常被问到的问题是，它如何与现有系统集成？
So we believe that NDN has a lot of potential in dynamic edge computing and
因此我们相信NDN在动态边缘计算中有很大的潜力，并且
orchestration.
orchestration.
When you're trying to put together your data, software and
当你尝试将你的数据、软件以及
hardware, trying to bring them together in real time and do compute.
硬件，尝试将它们实时整合起来并进行计算。
But when we started looking at that, the first question we get asked is okay we
但是当我们开始研究这个问题时，我们首先被问到的问题是好的，我们
have Kubernetes we have this, that and the other.
我们有Kubernetes，我们有这个、那个以及其他的。
How does it compare with that?
它与那个相比如何？
So that is one of the first things you have to do is look at existing systems.
因此，你首先要做的事情之一就是研究现有的系统。
And even if we have a great solution, either it has to somehow coexist with it,
即使我们有了一个很好的解决方案，它也必须以某种方式与现有系统共存。
interface with it.
它必须以某种方式与之接口对接。
So in my opinion, the NDN community can make
所以在我看来，NDN社区可以做出
much bigger impact, if you start looking at these sort of verticals or
行业垂直领域进行研究的话，影响力会更大。如果你开始关注这些类型的
solutions to solve specific problems and say, this is how we can do it.
解决特定问题的方案，就是说，我们可以这样做。
Now, you don't need to develop a full commercial solutions.
现在，你不需要开发完整的商业解决方案。
But even if you take an abstraction and say,
但即使你抽象地说，
this is how typically they are done in some example system.
这通常是它们在某些示例系统中的实现方式。
And this is how we can interface with it or
这就是我们如何与之交互的方式，或者
this is how we can make it so much better.
这就是我们如何能够让它变得更好。
So, that is kind of what I wanted to leave you with and
所以，这大概就是我想给你留下的东西，以及
sort of get you thinking on a topic.
所以这大概就是我想让你开始思考一个话题的东西。
And we also believe that when it comes to dynamic composable edge computing,
我们还相信，当涉及到动态可组合的边缘计算时，
there aren't many solutions out there.
目前还没有太多的解决方案。
And so it's a great area for the community to develop more support,
因此，这是一个很好的领域，社区可以在此发展更多的支持，
and also enhance the support for NDN over wireless.
因此，这也增强了对无线环境下NDN的支持。
Because when we started using any NDSM,
因为当我们开始使用任何NDSM时，
We found that there were a lot of things that could be done better, for instance,
我们发现有许多事情可以做得更好，例如，
just creating dynamic faces, deleting them and so on.
只是创建动态面孔，删除它们等等。
So this concludes my talk and I wanted to leave you with some of these
所以这就结束了我的演讲，我想给你们留下一些这些
points to think about and I wanted to see if there any questions.
要思考的一些要点，我想知道是否有任何问题。
If not, Eve, I'll hand it back to you.
如果没有问题，Eve，我会把它交还给你。
>> Okay.
>> 好的。
Anybody out there who would like to means a question?
有没有人想问一个问题？
>> Maybe what is the status of the program today?
也许现在程序的状态是怎样的？
>> So we are in final stages pretty much just winding down.
>> 所以我们基本上已经处于最后阶段，只是在收尾了。
We had the final workshop in June this year, so at this point,
我们在今年六月份进行了最后一次研讨会，所以到目前为止，
pretty much tying up some loose ends and that's pretty much it.
基本上是解决了一些尾巴问题，差不多就是这样了。
>> Catchavin can you speak to your own interest in directions for
Catchavin，你能谈谈你对未来方向的兴趣吗？
this work having been exposed to these teams.
这项工作已经被这些团队所了解。
>> Great question and thank you Eve.
这是一个很好的问题，谢谢你，Eve。
So as I eluded, one of the things and
所以正如我所暗示的，其中一件事情是
it was, the last slide was sort of related to that.
它是的，最后一张幻灯片与此有些关联。
So of course, being an Intel and
所以当然，作为一个英特尔和~!@#$%^&*()
also looking at the, where we believe that there's a lot of potential for
我们也在关注那些我们认为有很大潜力的领域。
NDN is in dynamic networks and for compute.
NDN在动态网络中以及用于计算。
I know NDN was traditionally developed for data over fixed networks, but
我知道NDN最初是为固定网络上的数据传输而开发的，但
at least if we want to bring these solutions into industry, there are a lot
至少如果我们想要将这些解决方案应用到工业领域，还有很多需要填补的空白，无论是NDN还是其他方面都需要填补。
of gaps that need to be filled, NDN or otherwise gaps need to be filled.
存在许多需要填补的空白，无论是NDN还是其他方面都需要填补。
There are so many devices, compute at the edges.
边缘处有如此多的设备，边缘计算正在进行。
Data being generated at the edges, also resources at the edges.
边缘产生的数据，边缘也有资源。
So, we're no longer limited to just the infrastructure having resources.
因此，我们不再仅限于基础设施拥有资源。
Resources can be anywhere, it can be a zeon in a car.
资源可以存在于任何地方，它可以是汽车中的一个zeon。
It can be a laptop in a user's home or a PC and so on.
它可以是用户家中的笔记本电脑或者是个人电脑等等。
How do we bring all of these into the fold of edge computing?
我们如何将所有这些内容纳入边缘计算的范畴？
And I believe NDN has a lot of potential there.
我相信NDN在那里有很大的潜力。
So I would definitely encourage the community as well to look more into it.
所以我也非常鼓励社区更多地深入了解这个问题。
>> We have a question here.
我们这里有一个问题。
>> Yes?
是的？
>> I was just going to read it, from Kathy Nichols.
我正打算读它，来自Kathy Nichols的。
Do you have a list of your top applications
您有没有一个您最喜欢的应用程序列表？
that could use dynamic composable solutions?
那能使用动态组合解决方案吗？
>> I think yeah, I think it is as the, at some instance as the question says itself.
我认为是的，我认为在某些情况下，正如问题本身所述。
The applications in our mind that typically need that and
我们通常认为需要那样做的应用场景有……
I'm sure there are more, it would be great for everyone to think about it.
我相信还有更多，大家思考一下会很好。
Typically of course, anything is related to smart transportation.
通常情况下，任何事物都与智能交通有关。
It has mobility, it has wireless, it has mobile resources and so on,
它具有移动性，它具有无线功能，它拥有移动资源等等，
our smart factory, cloud gaming, ARVR.
我们的智能工厂、云游戏、增强现实与虚拟现实。
So these are some of the things that come to mind, but I'm sure if you think about
所以这些是我想到的一些事情，但我相信如果你仔细思考
it, there may be others that you can come up with as well.
你也许还能想到其他的一些事情。
It's just that, if they have the competence of dynamism,
它们只是如果具备了动态的能力，
whether the network's changing, whether there's wireless,
无论网络是否在变化，无论是否有无线，
whether there's mobility, just think of.
无论是否有移动性，只需考虑。
And then along with some strict latency requirements,
然后再加上一些严格的延迟要求，
it provides a great combination in my mind.
它在我看来提供了一个很好的结合。
>> Okay, any further questions?
>> 还有其他问题吗？
Okay, well thank you very much, Kathyayani.
好的，非常感谢你，Kathyayani。
>> Thank you.
>> 谢谢你。
We have a second talk or second presentation.
我们有第二个讲话或第二场演讲。
I'd like to introduce the topic is on SPLICE,
我想介绍的主题是SPLICE，
Secure Predictively Low-Latency Information Centric Edge for
安全预测性低延迟信息中心边缘技术用于
next generation wireless networks.
下一代无线网络。
And the presentation will be given by Srinivas Shakkottai, who in 2007
received his PhD from the University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign.
received his PhD from the University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign.
他在伊利诺伊大学厄巴纳-香槟分校获得了博士学位。
And he was a postdoctoral scholar at Stanford.
他曾是斯坦福大学的博士后研究员。
He currently is a professor at Texas A&M University in the Department of Electrical
他目前是德克萨斯A&M大学电气系的教授。
and Computer Engineering.
以及计算机工程。
And his research interests include caching content distribution,
以及他的研究兴趣包括缓存内容分发，
network markets, multi agent learning and game theory,
网络市场、多智能体学习和博弈论，
wireless networks, reinforcement learning, as well as data collection and analytics.
无线网络、强化学习以及数据收集和分析。
Srinivas is the recipient, oops, somebody's typing very loudly.
Srinivas是获奖者，哎呀，有人打字声音很大。
Srinivas is the recipient of a Defense Threat Reduction agency young
Srinivas是国防威胁减少局青年
Investigator Award, and
调查员奖项，以及
NSF Career Award, as well as research awards from Cisco and Google.
国家科学基金会职业奖，以及来自思科和谷歌的研究奖项。
And a taboo, he also was received several other awards including
以及一个禁忌，他还获得了其他几个奖项，包括
an outstanding professor award and an engineering genesis award.
一个杰出教授奖和一个工程创世奖。
Srinivas, it's all yours.
斯里尼瓦斯，这全归你了。
>> Thank you, thank you all for being here.
>> 谢谢你们，感谢大家的到来。
So, I'll try to keep it reasonably concise.
所以，我会尽量保持简洁。
This is actually the combination of three years of research by several universities,
这其实是几所大学三年研究的结合。
several researchers.
这是几位研究员。
So SPLICE stands for, Secure Predictive Low-Latency Information Centric Edge.
所以SPLICE代表的是安全的、可预测的、低延迟的信息中心边缘。
And the goal was to work it into next generation wireless.
目标是将其融入到下一代无线技术中。
So that's the kind of ultimate aim.
所以那就是最终的目标。
So this project was across multiple universities, five of them.
所以这个项目是跨越了多所大学进行的，一共五所。
From Texas A&M, P R Kumar, and I'm giving this talk essentially for him.
来自德克萨斯A&M大学的P R Kumar，我基本上是代表他来做这次演讲的。
So there's Kumar, myself, and I-H.Hou from Texas A&M.
所以有Kumar，我自己，还有来自德克萨斯A&M大学的I-H.Hou。
There's Shroff and Attila Errol Masse from Ohio State,
有Shroff和来自俄亥俄州立大学的Attila Errol Masse。
Rheumatoid Charles Murray from Illinois, Alisa Bertino, and
查尔斯·默里来自伊利诺伊州，阿丽莎·贝蒂诺，以及
Charlie Hu from Purdue, and Patrick Rowley from WashU St. Louis.
查理·胡来自普渡大学，帕特里克·罗利来自圣路易斯华盛顿大学。
So if you look at this team,
所以如果你看看这个团队，
we are composed of folks doing wireless security scheduling, and
我们团队由从事无线安全调度的人员组成，以及
Patrick going in was the only person strongly invested in NDN specifically.
帕特里克是唯一一个特别投入于NDN的人。
And so, this has been a good deal of a learning experience for
这对我们其他人来说也是一个很好的学习经历。
the rest of us as well.
我们其他人也是一样。
Because we went in thinking that NDN as a very interesting
我们进去的时候认为NDN非常有趣，
kind of scheme of things, but with little experience with actually working with it.
在整个计划中我们只是略知一二，但实际上并没有太多与之工作的经验。
And when we came away, we were kind of solidly invested in the functionalities
当我们离开时，我们已经相当深入地投入到这些功能中了。
deploys, as well as being able to contribute to its enhancement.
部署，以及能够为其增强做出贡献。
So what was the point of this project?
那么这个项目的目的是什么？
Our goal was when we went in,
我们进入时的目标是，
we were trying to understand what is a worthwhile kind of application?
我们进入时的目标是，试图理解什么样的应用是值得的？
the wireless edge which doesn't exist today in some sense?
无线边缘在某种意义上今天并不存在吗？
And which is kind of very clearly obvious going forward.
而这在未来将会变得非常明显。
And we were kind of thinking about applications
我们在思考应用程序的可能性。
in that you're doing control of systems over wireless networks.
在这方面，您是通过无线网络对系统进行控制。
So in many of these control systems,
所以在许多这样的控制系统中，
what you wish to do is kind of reconstruct a physical or virtual theme.
你想做的是在某种程度上重建一个物理的或虚拟的主题。
For example, if you think about autonomous vehicles,
例如，如果你考虑自动驾驶汽车，
you have some vehicles with Lidar, some with cameras, some with radar, etc.
你有一些配备了激光雷达的车辆，一些配备了摄像头的，一些配备了雷达等等。
And what the vehicles are interested in is an abstraction of the physical field,
而车辆关心的是物理场的一个抽象，
what is located where, where are roads, people bicycles, etc.
它们位于何处，哪里有道路、人、自行车等。
So you're interested in reconstructing a physical dynamic field at all these nodes
所以你对在所有这些节点重建一个物理动态场感兴趣。
and then they wish to take some control action.
然后他们希望采取一些控制行动。
Similarly, if you think of virtual reality, we were thinking specifically of
同样地，如果你考虑虚拟现实，我们特别想到的是
virtual reality multiplayer gaming, in which again, you have a virtual field.
虚拟现实多人游戏，在这里你再次拥有一个虚拟的场地。
You've got all these monsters and walls and etc, all happening.
你会遇到各种怪物、墙壁等等，这些都是实时发生的。
You're events which are going on which is who is where,
你会遇到正在发生的事件，比如谁在哪里，
who is shooting at what, etc.
谁在向什么射击等等。
Or if it's a driving game, where these vehicles are moving, etc.
或者如果是一款赛车游戏，这些车辆在哪里移动等等。
And that virtual field needs to be reconstructed
而那个虚拟场地需要被重建。
with minimal delay at all the agents, the game players in question, right?
在所有代理商这里几乎没有任何延迟，对吧，就是那些游戏玩家？
In both these if you think about it, there is a good deal of commonality,
在这两种情况下，如果你仔细想想，它们之间有很多共同点，
you want a similar reconstruction at all these agents in terms of the field and
你希望在这些代理商中，就领域而言，实现类似的重建。
what the things are where.
这些东西在哪里。
So there is a good deal of correlation across user information requirements.
因此，在用户信息需求之间存在很多相关性。
And so what really the user or
因此，用户或者应用程序真正想要的是专注于提取所需信息。
the application really wants is to focus on extracting the desired information.
因此，应用程序真正想要的是专注于提取所需信息。
For example, in virtual reality, there is a so
例如，在虚拟现实中，有一个所谓的动作到光子延迟要求。
called motion to photon latency requirement.
称为动作到光子延迟要求。
In the sense that to move your head,
在这个意义上，为了移动你的头部，
you need a different viewpoint within roughly 12 to 15 milliseconds.
你需要在大约12到15毫秒内改变视角。
So that's pretty strict, because within that that time duration,
所以这是相当严格的，因为在那个时间段内，
you need to kind of identify what the user wants,
你需要某种程度上识别出用户想要什么，
to render that particular viewpoint, shift that viewpoint.
要渲染那个特定的视角，就得转换那个视角。
If you're doing wirelessly, the viewpoint, the information corresponding to it, has
to be transmitted over the airwaves.
to wind up at the user headset, it has to be uncompressed and displayed to the user.
要在用户的耳机上结束，它必须被解压并显示给用户。
And if you increase the latency, user start getting nauseated, etc.
如果增加延迟，用户开始感到恶心等不适。
Which is why really, when you look at the systems like Oculus, they have got a big
这就是为什么当你真正去了解像Oculus这样的系统时，你会发现它们有一个大型的
rendering engine, a big edge compute box sitting in your living room or wherever.
渲染引擎，一个大型的边缘计算盒子放置在你的客厅或其他地方。
And you've got a cable connecting the headset to the box so that you have very,
你有一根电缆将头戴设备连接到盒子上，这样你就能拥有非常低的延迟。
very low latency.
非常低的延迟。
Now if you want to cut that cable, if you want to make everything wireless,
现在，如果你想要剪断那根电缆，如果你想让一切都变成无线的，
that imposes quite a lot of constrictions on the information requirement as well as
对信息需求以及也造成了相当多的限制。
the wireless network itself.
无线网络本身。
Which is why we are focusing on controllable wireless delivery modalities.
这就是为什么我们专注于可控的无线传输方式。
How do we change the wireless network itself?
我们如何改变无线网络本身？
Primarily we'll be focusing on MAC scheduling algorithms,
我们主要将关注MAC调度算法，
keeping application performance and definitely security in mind.
我们将牢记保持应用性能和确保安全性。
In terms of security,
在安全性方面，
we were interested in the wireless angle in terms of connectivity.
我们对于无线方面的连接性很感兴趣。
As well as the information angle in terms of encryption decryption in the NDN
我们也对NDN中加密解密方面的信息角度非常感兴趣。
context.
上下文。
So in that context, we were trying to build a kind of system from
所以在那种上下文中，我们试图从头开始构建一种系统，在这种系统中我们可以基本上控制每一层。
the ground up in which we can essentially control every layer.
从头开始，我们基本上可以控制每一层。
Ideally using a combination of kind of custom software and hardware.
理想情况下，结合使用定制的软件和硬件。
So if you look at the lowest layer here, the blue one,
所以如果你看这里最底层的这一层，蓝色的那一层，
it is basically the wireless angle.
它基本上是无线通信的角度。
So what we've got there is a software defined radio in which we have full access
所以我们拥有的是一台软件定义无线电，我们可以完全访问它。
to the complete fine MAC, right?
我们可以完全访问到精细的MAC层，对吗？
And going up into the network stack,
我们向上进入网络栈，
you have the host machine in which you have the network stack as well.
您有一台主机，其中也包含了网络栈。
So in other words, these USRPs are the software defined radios connected to
所以换句话说，这些USRP就是连接到软件定义无线电的设备。
a kind of a controllerless scheme of things which is based on LabVIEW, right?
一种基于LabVIEW的无控制器方案，对吗？
And in which we basically can do MAC based changes in MAC scheduling etc.
在这个基础上，我们基本上可以在MAC调度等方面进行基于MAC地址的更改。
And we connected up this UDP indicator there,
我们在那里连接了这个UDP指示器，
is a local connection within a machine, it's not a TCP IP over the air.
是机器内部的本地连接，不是通过空中的TCP IP连接。
It is only UDP within to connect LabVIEW to the local host.
它仅使用UDP在内部连接LabVIEW至本地主机。
And then onwards we have the NFD stack and the applications.
然后我们有了NFD堆栈和应用程序。
So essentially what this is, if you will, is a kind of pure or semi pure information
所以本质上，如果你愿意的话，这是一种纯粹或半纯粹的信息
centric architecture wherein TCP IP is actually not even required, right?
因此，在本质上，如果你愿意的话，这是一种纯粹或半纯粹的信息中心架构，在这种架构中，实际上甚至不需要TCP/IP，对吧？
As I said, we use that UDP for
正如我所说，我们使用那个UDP来进行
a local connection because LabVIEW is capable of local UDP sockets.
因为LabVIEW能够处理本地UDP套接字，所以它是一种本地连接。
But the end to end from the server to the client is not a TCP IP connection at all.
但是从服务器到客户端的端到端连接根本不是TCP/IP连接。
The only thing which is connecting them are MAC IDs.
连接它们的唯一东西是MAC ID。
So the USRP uses a MAC ID and the other USRP uses this MAC ID
因此，一个USRP使用MAC ID，另一个USRP使用这个MAC ID。
to determine where it is coming from and who it is destined for.
为了确定它来自哪里以及它的目的地是哪里。
So that's our general architecture.
所以这就是我们的总体架构。
And I want to spend the next few minutes discussing what we attained or
接下来的几分钟里，我想讨论我们实现了什么或者
what are the goals of each level of this.
这几个层级的目标是什么。
And how we kind of went towards this ultimate goal of field reconstruction and
我们是如何朝着这个最终目标即田野重构迈进的。
control.
控制。
So if you look at this bottom most layer,
所以如果你看这个最底层，
the question is can we use an off the shelf wireless communication scheme?
问题是我们能否使用现成的无线通信方案？
For example, there is WiFi, which is essentially based on
例如，有WiFi，它本质上是基于
carrier sense multiple access back offs, so distributed.
载波侦听多路访问退避，因此是分布式的。
And LTE which is more scheduled.
而LTE则是更加有计划的调度。
Now if you want to attend latency guarantees, recollect this business of
现在如果你想要确保延迟的保证，请记住这件事情，
virtual reality requiring about 15 or so milliseconds latency.
如果你需要的是大约15毫秒左右的延迟来满足虚拟现实的要求。
Essentially, we calculated that if you need that kind of latency,
基本上，我们计算出如果你需要那种大约15毫秒左右的延迟来满足虚拟现实的要求。
the rendering is going to take quite a while, roughly four or five milliseconds,
渲染将会花费一些时间，大约需要四到五毫秒左右，
then there's compression.
然后是压缩。
It turns out that the wireless angle, the one half wireless,
原来是无线角度，半边无线，
you have about two ish milliseconds, maybe three.
你大约有两毫秒左右的时间，也许是三毫秒。
So essentially we needed a scheme wherein we can guarantee per packet latencies
所以本质上我们需要一个方案，能够保证每个数据包的延迟时间。
of less than two to three milliseconds, right?
所以本质上我们需要一个方案，能够保证每个数据包的延迟时间少于两到三毫秒，对吧？
Now the problem with WiFi is, given the critical flows exists because it's CSMA,
现在WiFi存在的问题是，由于它是CSMA，关键流存在的原因是这样的，
you have no guarantee whatsoever.
你根本没有任何保证。
If you look at LTE 4G, basically, the frame length is ten milliseconds.
如果你看一下LTE 4G，基本上，帧长度是十毫秒。
But the problem is, when you transmit a packet,
但问题在于，当你传输一个数据包时，
the ack comes back either as a bundled ack, or
ack要么作为捆绑式应答返回，要么
you have to schedule the ack, which is seven milliseconds away at the minimum.
你必须安排ACK的调度，其最小延迟为七毫秒。
So in other words, LTE is not capable of this low latency kind of scheme.
换句话说，LTE不能实现这种低延迟的方案。
And remember, when we were doing this 5G was in its infancy.
还记得，当时我们在做这个的时候，5G还处于起步阶段。
Indeed, even now, 5G deployments with ultra low latency are fairly minimal.
的确，即便是现在，具有超低延迟的5G部署仍然相当有限。
So essentially what we were looking for
所以本质上我们在寻找的是
was our own custom NDN friendly ultra low latency scheme, right?
所以本质上我们在寻找的是我们自己定制的、对NDN友好的超低延迟方案，对吗？
And so the edge of information has to decide to do this idea.
所以信息的边缘必须决定去实施这个想法。
That essentially we are doing field reconstruction.
这本质上是我们在做场的重建。
And the value of the field is as good as how it represents reality.
这个领域的价值在于它对现实的准确反映。
So if you're looking at autonomous driving, if a certain object has moved and
所以如果你在研究自动驾驶，如果某个物体已经移动了并且
you don't know about it, well your field,
你对此一无所知，好吧，你的领域，
your perception of reality is different from reality itself.
你对现实的感知与现实本身是不同的。
your perception of it is the edge of information.
你对它的感知是信息的边缘。
So you want to minimize this edge of information.
所以你想要尽量减少这种信息的边缘。
This applies even in virtual reality regime,
这甚至适用于虚拟现实环境中，
in the sense that there is a monster in front of you or next to you, etc.
在这种意义上，有一个怪物在你的前面或者旁边等等。
Where is the monster as far as the canonical virtual world is concerned
在规范虚拟世界里，这个怪物在哪里？
versus where is it with respect to where you are, I mean, your perception of it?
相对于你所在的位置，这个怪物在哪里？我的意思是，你对它的感知在哪里？
So you want to minimize that that difference in perception, right?.
所以你想要尽量减少那种感知上的差异，对吗？
Now we said that there are multiple users and so there's correlation across them.
现在我们说有多个用户，所以他们之间存在相关性。
So we wanted to build in some level of multicast support.
所以我们想要在某种程度上加入多播支持。
And indeed NDN awareness in the sense that we need to tie this in into NDN.
确实，我们需要将这一点融入到NDN中，以增强对NDN的认识。
So that the NDN packets that are issued, requests, interest packets and
所以发出的NDN数据包，请求，兴趣包以及
the responses etc are kind of cleanly integrated into the wireless layer.
这些响应等在无线层中得到了比较清晰的集成。
So that they can reveal in some sense what their latency requirements are etc, and
这样他们在某种程度上可以揭示出他们的延迟要求等信息，以及
we can integrate it and support it.
我们可以将其整合并提供支持。
So I'm gonna give you one slide on one of the major results.
所以我将为你展示一个关于主要成果之一的幻灯片。
So essentially, the very first one is what I'm going to talk about.
所以本质上，我将要讲述的就是第一个主题。
In which way we instantiated, we developed delay scheduling algorithms which
在我们实例化的方式中，我们开发了延迟调度算法，它可以
maximize the delay sensitive throughput, we call this timely throughput.
在我们的实例化方式中，我们开发了延迟敏感吞吐量最大化算法，我们称之为及时吞吐量。
And we basically actually instantiated it on USRPs.
我们基本上实际上是在USRPs上实例化了它。
After that there were several papers on actually integrating it into various
之后有几篇论文实际上将其整合到了各种不同的~!@#$%^&*()
regimes.
政权。
And the last one was actually that since we had this platform where we could
为了能够在各个不同层面上控制系统，我们实际上构建了一个RL平台，
a reinforcement learning platform to do auto configuration.
一个用于自动配置的强化学习平台。
So that was the very end of this, which appeared last year.
这就是去年出现的这件事情的最后部分。
But I just want to tell you about the capacity region,
但我只是想告诉你关于容量区域，
I think, by our low latency scheduling algorithms.
我认为，通过我们的低延迟调度算法。
So what this diagram shows is basically the real time versus the non real time.
所以这张图表基本上展示的是实时与非实时之间的对比。
Traffic supportable simultaneously by a wireless channel of 20 megahertz, right.
无线信道在20兆赫频宽下同时支持的流量，对。
So the leftmost one is our scheduling scheme.
所以最左边的是我们的调度方案。
Wherein you notice that it attains the full convex region.
在这里你会注意到它达到了完整的凸区域。
Whereas other schemes such as just longest few first, max weight basically, or
而其他的策略，例如最长优先、基本上是最大权重，或者
random policies or round robin etc are unable to attain.
随机策略或循环轮询等无法实现的。
So basically, we're able to show that analytically valuable kind of takeaways in
因此，基本上我们能够展示在分析上有价值的收获在
terms of the scheduling algorithms actually have an impact in reality.
调度算法的条款实际上在现实中有所影响。
You're able to support a larger region of operations.
你能够支持更大范围的操作。
Now, moving up to the NDN scheme of things and caching.
现在，让我们来谈谈NDN架构的事情以及缓存技术。
Essentially our our thought process with the NDN was that
基本上，我们对NDN的思考过程是这样的
one big advantage that NDN provides is information reuse.
NDN提供的一个重大优势是信息重用。
That is it is cached at multiple locations in the content stores that are available.
即它被缓存在多个可用的内容存储位置中。
And so essentially can be utilized, one,
因此，本质上可以被利用，一是，
this this kind of stream of names going by because you see the names.
这种名字流过去，因为你看到了这些名字。
Can you predict what name will be requested next essentially by
你能预测出接下来会有哪个名字被提出来吗，本质上通过~!@#$%^&*()
multiple streams as these names go by?
能否通过这些名字的流转来预测出多个可能性？
And can you therefore determine in advance what might be requested and
是否因此能够预先确定可能会被请求的内容？
cache it in advance?
是否因此能够预先缓存？
Now of course NDN is opportunistic, we want it to be and
现在当然了，NDN是机会主义的，我们希望它是这样的，并且
make it basically predictable, right?
让它基本上可以预测，对吗？
So the scheme of things they were we wanted to have a way of doing proactive
所以我们想要一种主动的方式来安排事务。
requesting.
我们需要请求。
We needed to build this into NDN.
我们需要将这个构建进NDN中。
So we had some NFD modifications to allow this to happen.
所以我们对NFD进行了一些修改，以便实现这一点。
And furthermore, we wanted to actually provide latency guarantees via smart
因此，我们想要通过智能方式实际提供延迟保证。
caching algorithms which can actually prefetch the items which are needed.
缓存算法可以实际预取所需的项目。
Again we need wireless awareness because the link may be lossy, etc.
我们再次需要无线连接意识，因为连接可能会有丢失等问题。
So identifying which links to focus on for
我们需要识别出哪些连接是我们应该重点关注的，以便于——
such predictions and how much you can do prediction versus opportunistic, etc.
这些预测以及你能在多大程度上进行预测与抓住机遇等问题。
Are questions which we have to deal with with respect to the wireless link.
这些都是我们必须处理的与无线连接相关的问题。
So in this context, we had a whole bunch of work.
所以在这种情况下，我们有一大堆工作要做。
The first three are more related to NFD modifications, our
前三者更多地与NFD的修改有关，我们的
own kind of flavor of NFD, which basically allows you to kind of prerequest stuff.
我们自己的NFD风格，基本上允许你预先请求一些东西。
Because if you think about it,
因为如果你仔细想一想，
NFD by itself is not really issuing interests of its own, right.
NFD本身并没有真正发行它自己的利益，对吧。
And so what we did was we basically stuck in an algorithm as it were a small module,
所以我们所做的就是基本上插入了一个算法，就像是一个小模块，
which looks at the stream of interest going by, and
它观察着流动的利息，并且
issues interest natively from NFT itself.
它自然地从NFT本身产生兴趣。
So that these interest when they're satisfied will come and
因此，当这些兴趣得到满足时，它们将会涌现。
sit in the caching, the content store of the loaded question.
因此，缓存中会保存已加载问题的内容存储。
And so are available closer to the end user even before the end user actually
因此，即使在终端用户实际上还未
issues of interest.
感兴趣的问题。
So, essentially we worked on proactive requests.
所以，本质上我们致力于主动请求。
This was mostly focused on by the folks at washu.
这主要是由华盛顿大学的研究人员所关注的。
Then we use some of these ideas for enabling these predictive requests,
然后我们利用这些想法来实现这些预测性请求，
as I said to NFD modifications.
然后我们利用这些想法来实现这些预测性请求，正如我之前提到的NFD修改。Another strain of thought was, if you're really interested in low latency,
Another strain of thought was, if you're really interested in low latency,
另一种思考方式是，如果你真的对低延迟感兴趣，
perhaps the NFD forwarding scheme of things needs optimization.
也许NFD转发方案需要优化。
And so, some folks actually worked on that kind of
因此，有些人实际上致力于这种工作。
evaluating different forwarding schemes including hardware based forwarding.
评估不同的转发方案，包括基于硬件的转发。
In order to reduce the latency of NDN Forwarding,
为了减少NDN转发的延迟，
specifically when you scale up to larger amounts of traffic, right?
特别是当你扩大到更大量的流量时，对吧？
On the Caching side,
在缓存方面，
we had several fundamental results, specifically based on unreliable channels.
我们得到了几个基本结果，特别是基于不可靠通道的研究。
We found several counterintuitive results on when you should cache and
我们发现了一些违反直觉的结果，关于你应该何时缓存
how much you should distribute your cache memories.
你应该如何分配你的缓存内存。
So that's where I'll stop with respect to this.
那么关于这个问题，我就讲到这里。
An implementation, which we had to do with virtual reality.
一个我们必须用到虚拟现实技术来实现的项目。
This was integration of the whole system, wherein you have the VR headset,
这是整个系统的集成，其中你有VR头戴设备，
you have caches of NDN basically, as well as the wireless channel underneath.
你拥有NDN的缓存，并且还有底层的无线信道。
And this is not a video it's just a frame, please.
这不是一个视频，它只是一个画面，请注意。
Basically we were able to show I think you should be able to see it on your screens.
基本上我们能够展示出来，我认为你们应该能在屏幕上看到它。
The top left is with predictive, we are able to support a much higher rate of high
左上角是带有预测功能的，我们能够支持一个更高频率的高解析度帧率。
resolution frames than the bottom right, which is should look kind of grainy.
右下角应该看起来有点粗糙，分辨率帧比左上角要低。
So you actually see this as you play the game,
所以你在玩游戏的时候实际上会看到这个情况，
you can see that a good deal more is at a much higher resolution,
你会发现更多的内容都以更高的分辨率呈现。
you can pretty much make sure that most of them are at high resolution.
你几乎可以确信它们中的大多数都是高分辨率的。
Only a few will be at the lower resolution.
只有少数会是低分辨率的。
So that was kind of so we were able to improve the end user quality of experience
所以这就是我们能够提高最终用户体验质量的原因。
by tying in caching as well as the wireless.
通过结合缓存以及无线技术。
And so the final thing I just mentioned the VR App,
所以我刚才提到的最后一件事，即VR应用，
the high level goal of VR App in general was to cut the cord.
一般而言，VR应用的高级目标是实现无线化。
So when I began this talk I talked about essentially Oculus, and
所以当我开始这个演讲时，我主要谈的是Oculus，以及
the fact that you need a cable between the edge rendering box and your headset.
事实上，你需要一根电缆连接边缘渲染盒和你的头戴设备。
The goal was to actually eliminate that via smart wireless scheduling and
目标实际上是通过智能无线调度来消除这种需求。
prefetching.
预取。
So that via the use of NDN, basically for
因此通过使用NDN，基本上是为了
this kind of communication, right.
这种通信方式，对。
Now finally, of course, we needed this whole system to be secured by design.
现在最终，当然，我们需要这整个系统从设计上就是安全的。
So essentially, we needed the questions of access control security and
所以本质上，我们需要解决访问控制安全问题和信息安全问题。
information security.
信息安全。
And the information security,
信息安全，
the first two bullet points there, indicate that we need latency guarantees.
前两个要点表明，我们需要延迟保证。
Because we do not have infinite time we only have about 14 or
因为我们没有无限的时间，我们只有大约14或者
so milliseconds before the next frame shows up at the headset.
所以，基本上如果我们意识到我们没有时间去浪费两毫秒或者在下一帧出现在头显之前。
three milliseconds in encryption decryption.
在加密解密中的三毫秒。
So, we wanted lightweight encryption schemes, and
所以，我们需要轻量级加密方案，以及
that was pretty much the focus of Lisa Martino's group.
这基本上是丽莎·马蒂诺小组的重点。
As well as looking at essentially access control methods, she focused primarily
她主要关注的是基本上的访问控制方法。
on LTE because we realize going forward 5G is going to be based on LTE.
在LTE上，因为我们意识到未来5G将会基于LTE。
And many of our scheduling algorithms etcetera,
以及我们的许多调度算法等等，
would have a natural home in 5G in some sense.
在某种意义上，将会在5G中找到一个自然的归宿。
Although as things have developed over the past three years, it's
尽管在过去三年的发展中，它已经
even Wi-Fi has moved towards a scheduling based scheme, Wi-Fi 6 and so on.
即使是Wi-Fi也已经朝着基于调度的方案发展，例如Wi-Fi 6等。
I love scheduling, so it's kind of interesting that both Wi-Fi and
我喜欢调度，所以Wi-Fi和
LTE or 5G are moving strongly towards the scheduled scheme of things as
LTE或5G正在大力推进计划化方案，因为
opposed to random access.
相对于随机接入而言。
So the main results from the security side.
因此，从安全性方面来看，主要的结果是。
The first few all have to do with access security, essentially looking for schemes,
前几个主要与接入安全有关，基本上是在寻找方案，
which are kind of poorly developed with respect to the security angle in LTE.
在LTE中，与安全角度相关的部分发展得相对薄弱。
The latter few are related to essentially signature schemes, encryption, decryption
后几个主要与签名方案、加密解密有关。
and that's really what I want to focus on as my kind of candidates slide.
这正是我想要重点关注的，作为我候选人策略的一部分。
So this basically indicates, >> If you could surely fast if you could
所以这基本上表明，>>如果你能肯定地快速地如果你能
wrap up shortly, that would be great.
如果您能尽快结束，那就太好了。
>> I'm done with the last slide basically.
>> 我基本上已经完成了最后一张幻灯片。
>> Okay.
>> 好的。
>> Oops, sorry.
>> 哎呀，不好意思。
So essentially what we had, we wanted to say that we had lightweight signature
所以本质上我们想说的是，我们有轻量级的签名
schemes, wherein you can actually encrypt decrypt much more quickly.
方案中，你实际上可以更快地进行加密解密。
So I have a slide on that actual system how it looked in terms of a access point,
所以我有一个关于那个实际系统的幻灯片，它在访问点方面是怎样的，
and multiple hosts.
以及多个主机。
And finally, this has to do with a little bit more on the system architecture, but
最后，这还与系统架构有一些更多的关联，但是
I'll wrap up there and say thank you.
我到此结束并说声谢谢。
>> Terrific, thank you.
非常好，谢谢。
Are there any questions?
有什么问题吗？
>> It says somebody I need a highlight.
>> 它说有人我需要一个亮点。
I don't want the paint.
我不想要油漆。
>> I don't know what the highlight is either [LAUGH].
>> 我也不知道重点是什么[笑]。
But actually, can you tell us where the work is going next?
但实际上，你能告诉我们下一步的工作计划吗？
>> So one aspect is we asked for a no cost extension and
我们申请了无成本延期，
we got some funds from the power testbeds
我们从电力测试平台获得了一些资金。
to try out some of these ideas over the air over reasonable ranges.
尝试通过空中在合理的距离上测试这些想法。
So we basically as far as this extension to power is a platform for
所以我们基本上认为这种权力扩展是一个平台用于
advanced wireless research.
所以我们基本上认为这种权力扩展是一个平台用于先进无线研究。And what we're doing there is working with the Utah test bed.
And what we're doing there is working with the Utah test bed
我们在那里所做的就是与犹他测试平台合作。
wherein they have got USRPs and SRSNT operating all of them.
他们在那里拥有USRPs和SRSNT，并且都在运行。
Where we want to try out this combination of low latency scheduling and
我们想要尝试这种低延迟调度和联合的组合，
NDN with the idea that if you think of things like autonomous vehicles and so on.
NDN借鉴了这样的想法，即如果你考虑像自动驾驶汽车之类的事物。
You are going to be operating them in the field, with these long range links.
你将会在野外使用它们，通过这些远程链接进行操作。
And the question was what kind of performance gains can we get using NDN for
我们能通过使用NDN获得哪些性能提升？
as a field reconstruction in the context of autonomous vehicles.
作为自动驾驶车辆背景下的场景重构。
That is one one train of thought which is continuing.
这是一个持续进行的思路。
This same idea we believe is valuable also in
我们相信这个相同的想法在……也是有价值的。
I think that was mentioned in the last session as well.
我认为在上一次会议中也提到了这个问题。
Essentially, it looks like it's the whole concept of ICN and
基本上，它看起来像是整个ICN的概念以及
NDN specifically seems to be quite valuable in the context of sharing
NDN在共享方面似乎特别有价值，在自治车辆的背景下，有很多共性的信息。
information with a lot of commonality in the context of autonomous vehicles.
在自治车辆的背景下，有很多共性的信息。
So that's
所以这就是~!@#$%^&*()
something which we think is valuable and something to look forward too.
我们认为有价值并值得期待的东西。
>> Thank you very much for your insights.
>> 非常感谢您的洞察。
That was terrific.
那真是太棒了。
>> Thank you.
>> 谢谢。
>> Okay, we're gonna hand over the floor to Jeff Burke, who's gonna speak to us.
>> 好的，我们将把讲话权交给Jeff Burke，他将向我们发言。
He's going to give us an update on ICN-Enabled Secure Edge Networking
他将向我们提供关于ICN支持的安全边缘网络的最新进展。
with Augmented Reality the ICE-AR project.
他将介绍增强现实技术在ICE-AR项目中的应用。
And for those of you who don't know him already,
对于那些还不了解他的人来说，
Jeff Burke is a Professor in Residence at the UCLA Department of Theater.
Jeff Burke 是加州大学洛杉矶分校戏剧系的常驻教授。
He co directs REMAP, the Center for Research and
他共同指导了REMAP研究中心，即研究与
Engineering Medium Performance.
他共同指导了REMAP研究中心，即研究与工程媒介表现的加州大学洛杉矶分校戏剧、电影与电视学院联合中心。
Television and the Samueli School of Engineering.
他共同指导了REMAP研究中心，即研究与工程媒介表现的加州大学洛杉矶分校戏剧、电影与电视学院联合中心。REMAP自2010年以来一直在NDN上进行应用研究，联合了戏剧、电影与电视学院和Samueli工程学院。
REMAP has conducted application research in NDN since 2010,
自2010年以来，REMAP在NDN上进行了应用研究，
and Jeff is a COPI in the NSF Intel Supported ICE-AR Program.
杰夫是NSF Intel支持的ICE-AR项目的合作主要研究员(COPI)。
All yours, Jeff.
都归你了，杰夫。
>> Great, thanks to you.
>> 太好了，多亏了你。
So this is collaborative work by the PI's that are listed in
所以这是列在幻灯片底部和一些也参与此次通话的首席研究员们的合作工作。
So at the end if you have questions, they're here as well.
所以如果你最后有任何问题，他们也会在这里。
I am going to give a quick overview of the ICE-AR program,
我将快速概述ICE-AR项目，
and talk a bit about the lessons that we've learned.
并谈一谈我们学到的一些教训。
And these are things that we've gone back and forth internally on quite a bit,
这些都是我们在内部反复讨论了很多次的事情。
both to share with Intel and NSF, and now with you.
既是为了与英特尔和国家科学基金会分享，现在也与您分享。
There are four research thrusts, one in applications that really led to API and
这里有四个研究重点，其中一个是在应用程序方面，这确实导致了API的发展，
library development as a big part of the project
项目的一个重要部分是库的开发。
as we navigated what exactly are applications needed.
在我们探索过程中，确切需要哪些应用程序。
One on security at the edge, one on information-centric wireless,
一个关于边缘安全的，一个关于信息中心无线的，
so the impact of a data centric NDN based approach on lower layer
所以基于数据中心的NDN方法对底层的影响
wireless technology in this edge context.
无线技术在这种边缘计算环境中的应用。
And then the use of acceleration as a service, and
接着是将加速作为一项服务的使用，以及
all of these were driven by the use of augmented reality and
这些都是通过使用增强现实来推动的，
layered mixed reality to drive research on NDN at the wireless edge.
这些都是通过使用分层混合现实来推动无线边缘网络中命名数据网络（NDN）的研究。
So on the website, there is a significant amount of code and
在网站上，有大量的代码和~!@#$%^&*()
more detailed publications.
更详细的出版物。
I'm gonna go pretty quickly through everything here.
我会在这里迅速地走过一切内容。
And so there's a lot more of a technical detail there.
因此，在那里有更多的技术细节。
So the original driver was decentralized augmented reality.
因此，最初的驱动因素是分散式增强现实。
So the basic idea is that for AR in the future,
因此，基本的想法是，对于未来的增强现实（AR），
we may move from applications that are centralized.
我们可能会从集中式的应用程序转变过来。
And they're delivered in a stovepipe context, both for the apps and
我们可能会从集中式的应用程序转变过来，它们在一个烟囱式的上下文中交付，无论是对于应用程序还是 the content to a decentralized approach, where individuals share their context,
the content to a decentralized approach, where individuals share their context,
内容转变为一种去中心化的方式，个人在其中分享他们的上下文环境，
things like location, camera view, and so on.
位置、摄像头视角等内容。
And in return, get content offers from many sources.
并且作为回报，从多个来源获取内容提供。
And that there are edge processing nodes that participate in both
并且有边缘处理节点参与其中
the calculation of the context or figuring out a deeper notion
计算上下文或者理解更深层次的概念
of context from the raw sensor readings on the phone, and
从手机上的原始传感器读数中计算上下文，以及
also then delivering customized content to an eventual AR experience.
还有为最终的增强现实体验提供定制内容。
And over the course of the project, I think we shifted on the application side
在项目过程中，我认为我们在应用方面进行了转变。
to not only looking at AR, but really looking at a more general shift in media
不仅仅关注增强现实（AR），而是真正关注媒体的更广泛转变。
and experience and delivery from an old model in which computation was kind of
和体验以及交付来自一个旧模式，在这个模式中，计算在某种程度上是
isolated at each stage of the production process.
在生产过程的每个阶段都是孤立的。
From envisioning the media, to making it, to delivering it, and experiencing it,
从构想媒体，到制作媒体，再到传递媒体，以及体验媒体，
to really a realtime model that's inspired by certainly the way the web works.
实现一个真正的实时模型，这一模型无疑是受到了网页运作方式的启发。
But also now, game engines, and some of the realtime 3D rendering tools
但现在，游戏引擎以及一些实时3D渲染工具
that are influencing AR VR cinematic production and so
正在影响AR VR电影制作等领域。
on, which presents a lot of interesting opportunities for edge computation,
正在为边缘计算带来许多有趣的机遇，
in which media is customized at the last possible moment.
在这种媒介中，内容是在最后可能的时刻进行定制的。
So the first of the ICE-AR thrusts was this application focus,
因此，ICE-AR项目的首要推动力是这种应用焦点，
and I'm actually not gonna discuss too much the AR and
我实际上不打算过多讨论增强现实技术(AR)相关的内容。
MR integration tests that were really driving our hands on experimentation.
MR集成测试确实推动了我们的实践实验。
And just wanna focus for this presentation on four outcomes,
并且我只想在这次演讲中专注于四个成果，
in terms of new APIs and libraries for the community.
在为社区提供新的API和库方面。
The first is called the Common Name Library, NDN-CNL.
第一个被称为通用名称库，NDN-CNL。
And this is a collection oriented API for NDN that kind of moves one layer up
这是一个面向NDN的集合导向API，它在某种程度上提升了一个层级。
from the interest data exchange that most of the existing APIs that handle.
从大多数现有API处理的兴趣数据交换开始。
And presents an alternative to a socket based way of thinking that focuses on
并提出了一种与基于套接字方式思考不同的替代方案，该方案侧重于
name based collections as the API for the application itself.
提出了一种以名称为基础的集合作为应用程序本身的API。
The second was a integration of our previous work on realtime
第二个是我们之前关于实时工作的整合。
video into a visual programming language called touch designer.
视频转换成一种名为Touch Designer的可视化编程语言。
This was called TouchNDN, so you'll see a little
这被称为TouchNDN，所以你会看到一点儿
bit in the video that probably is not playing very smoothly for you.
视频中的那一部分可能没有为你播放得很流畅。
But you get a rough idea of his visual programming environment for
但你大致可以了解他的视觉编程环境用于
experimenting with data centric media.
实验以数据为中心的媒体。
Then on the lower right is a stack diagram for NDN-Lite, which is the latest
然后在右下角是一个NDN-Lite的堆栈图，它是最新的
generation IoT framework kind of taking into account the needs of both easy and
考虑到易用性和生成物联网框架需求的一种框架。
cross platform deployment of NDN for IoT, and AR support context.
跨平台部署适用于物联网的NDN以及增强现实支持环境。
But also,
但也是，
trying to build on a lot of IoT work that's happened in the community before.
试图在之前社区中发生的大量物联网工作的基础上进行拓展。
And then finally, some approaches to remote procedure calls that would
旨在对远程过程调用的一些方法进行探索，这些方法将会
be used to generalize the way that we invoke remote services.
将用于推广我们调用远程服务的方式。
And some demonstration of how to modify existing video codecs to take advantage
以及一些如何修改现有视频编解码器以利用
of NDNs consumer driven approach to being able to select video both in space and
NDN消费者驱动方法的选择视频的空间和
time at the level of an individual, and the interest using names.
时间在个人层面上的应用，以及使用名称的兴趣。
And of course,
当然，
we're looking at security as being built into the applications into the network.
我们正在研究将安全性内置于应用程序和网络之中。
But really, from an NDN research point of view, focusing on continuing
但实际上，从一个NDN研究的角度来看，重点在于持续进行
the effort to dymatize security relationships through the use of names.
努力通过使用名称来使安全关系动态化。
And so there are several examples listed on this slide that range from
因此，在这张幻灯片上列出了几个不同的例子，涵盖了范围从……
new certificate schemes like Coalesce for efficient shortlived keys on IoT,
新的证书方案，如Coalesce，用于物联网上高效的短期密钥，
to continued work on our certificate infrastructure.
继续我们的证书基础设施工作。
Do some applications of attribute based cryptography that
应用基于属性的密码学进行一些应用，它能够
provide a nice bridge between what we can specify in a name,
提供了一个很好的桥梁，用于我们在名称中能够指定的内容，
in terms of the attributes that might allow verification
在可能允许验证的属性方面
of data with essentially policy in a way baked into the ABS certificates,
在ABS证书中以实质上将策略内置于数据之中的方式，
to access control of that context exchange that I mentioned earlier.
在我之前提到的那种上下文交换中进行访问控制。
And looking also finally at availability, and
并且最后还要考虑到可用性，以及
how to handle DDoS in these circumstances.
在这些情况下如何处理DDoS攻击。
So some of the security APIs are on the call, and
因此，一些安全API正在被调用，而且
I think might be interested in answering detailed questions if you'd like to
我认为如果您愿意的话，您可能会对回答详细问题感兴趣。
know more about the security work, sorry.
了解更多关于安全工作的信息，抱歉。
And then the third area of research was focused on the impact of an information,
然后第三个研究领域关注的是信息影响。
or data centric way of thinking on the wireless layer.
或者在无线层面上的数据中心思维方式。
And if you think about NDNs intrinsic multicast behavior, it's well suited for
如果你考虑到NDN天生的多播行为，它非常适合用于
wireless media, or at least, it should be well suited for
无线媒介，或者至少，它应该非常适合用于……
a media that is intrinsically broadcast.
一种天生就是广播的媒介。
But the common implementations of WiFi have been focused on unicast behavior.
但是WiFi的常见实现集中于单播行为。
So a lot of the effort in this thrust to the project was to find ways to actually
因此，该项目的一个重要工作重点是寻找实际的方法来...
take advantage and create high performance link layer wireless multicast
利用优势并创建高性能的链路层无线多播
that is leveraging the names that are available in NDN interest and data.
这是利用NDN兴趣和数据中可用的名字来发挥作用。
And at the same time, to take further advantage of those names to start doing
并且同时，进一步利用这些名字开始进行
runtime learning and reasoning about different types of failure modes.
运行时学习和推理关于不同类型的故障模式。
So both to look at the traffic patterns based on the names themselves, but also,
因此，既要根据名称本身来观察交通模式，也要，
things that can be encoded in interest as well.
因此，兴趣中也可以编码的事物。
And so some of the experimental results from the wireless group are listed below,
因此，无线小组的一些实验结果如下所示，
and include higher performance multicast, improved application speeds for AR and VR.
以及更高性能的组播、增强现实和虚拟现实应用的速度得到了改善。
And decreased packet loss in these high performance multicast situations,
以及在这些高性能组播情况下减少了数据包丢失，
as well as some implementation additions to Android WiFi direct
以及对Android WiFi直连进行了一些实现上的补充
that were important to the future of the applications that we were looking at.
这些对我们正在研究的应用程序的未来至关重要。
And then finally, as a kinda key example of an edge service well supported by NDN.
最后，作为一个由NDN很好支持的边缘服务的关键示例。
We looked at FPGA based acceleration taking,
我们考察了基于FPGA的加速技术，
in this particular case, an interest in trying to ingest at the edge,
在这种情况下，对于尝试在边缘进行数据摄取表现出了兴趣，
low latency content from the camera that's carried on a phone or
在这种情况下，对于尝试在边缘进行数据摄取表现出了兴趣，通过手机上携带的摄像头获得低延迟内容，
a headset, and go from unprocessed video.
一种耳机，从未经处理的视频开始。
That's something where there was some deep context about
这是某个有着深刻背景的东西，
what was happening with the human beings in the scene?
场景中的人类发生了什么事？
So we're interested in pose recognition as an initial sort of basis for
所以我们对姿态识别感兴趣，作为一种初始的基础，用于
understanding activity and human behavior.
理解活动和人类行为。
>> And Jason Collins group at UCLA worked on a novel FPGA acceleration
>> 加州大学洛杉矶分校的Jason Collins小组致力于研究一种新型的FPGA加速技术。
with low power, sort of a nice low power and high frame rate result.
这样可以实现低功耗和高帧率的优秀结果。
That was an example of what can then be plugged into an acceleration
这是一个可以插入加速器的示例。
as a service model, leveraging the work from Alicia Shanks group on
作为一种服务模式，利用了Alicia Shanks小组的工作成果，
this remote procedure call general mechanism.
这种远程过程调用的一般机制。
So I'm gonna use just a few minutes now at the end to talk about contributions and
所以现在我将利用最后的几分钟时间来谈谈贡献和
lessons learned.
所以现在我将利用最后的几分钟时间来谈谈贡献和吸取的教训。
Maybe focusing a little bit more on the lessons.
也许应该更多地关注所学到的教训。
What we saw, we believe is a further validation of the architecture and
我们所见证的，我们相信是对架构的进一步验证，以及它在促进这些无线边缘应用方面的方法。
its approach in benefiting these wireless edge applications.
它在促进这些无线边缘应用方面的方法。
I wanna point out just one thing in particular,
我想特别指出一件事情，
which is the middle bullet here on the network computation and storage.
这是网络计算和存储的中间要点。
And I would add actually content producers and
实际上，内容生产者和
consumers as well are all supplying the same data.
消费者们也都在提供相同的数据。
And so through seamless integration into an ecosystem of new devices from
因此通过无缝集成到新设备的生态系统中，从
IoT to media and I think one place where we saw that in a very concrete and
物联网到媒体，我认为我们在一个非常具体和~!@#$%^&*()
specific way in my are, which was focusing on applications was suddenly
特定的方式在我的领域，那就是突然专注于应用程序。
being able to look at video from several different perspectives.
能够从几个不同的角度查看视频。
Was it a bus that we could tap into a stream that we would receive in
我们可以接入的是一辆公交车吗，我们会收到的是一个流吗？
a traditional way or
一种传统的方式或者
essentially part of the key value store that really looked a lot like storage.
本质上是键值存储的一部分，这实际上非常类似于存储。
It actually didn't matter how the video was produced,
实际上，视频是如何制作的并不重要，
but by having it in the NDN packet format and on the network, we could use any of
但是通过将其置于NDN（命名数据网络）数据包格式并放在网络上，我们可以使用任何一种
those three approaches to access both live and historical video as an example
这三种方法作为一个例子，用于访问实时和历史视频。
of the sort of impact of the architecture on how we think about applications.
这种架构对我们思考应用程序可能产生的影响有着深刻的启示。
Also, the ICR project is definitely deepened our team's understanding of
此外，ICR项目无疑加深了我们团队对……的理解。
the impact of the network architecture both upwards and downwards.
网络架构向上和向下的影响。
So impacting lower layer technologies that are now optimized to support IP and
因此影响了现在为支持IP而优化的底层技术，
essentially point-to-point delivery mechanism most of the time as well as,
因此基本上是点对点传输机制的大部分时间以及，
of course, the impact on upper layer apps in terms of how they think
当然，这对于上层应用在它们的思考方式上的影响
about moving content around,
关于内容的移动，
making connections before they proceed with exchanging content and so on.
在他们继续交换内容等事宜之前建立联系。
Certainly there's impact in the middle and on the approach to security, as well.
当然，这种影响也存在于中间层以及安全方法上。
We saw I think from that impact on the upper and lower layers, some challenges
我们认为从那种对上层和下层的影响中，看到了一些挑战。
that we hadn't really expected on quantitative comparisons implementation.
我们确实没有预料到在量化比较的实施上，会有一些我们没有真正预期到的好的表现结果。
So certainly there are some nice performance results from the subareas that
我们确实看到了一些分领域内出乎意料的好的表现结果。
I mentioned briefly in the previous slides, but
我在之前的幻灯片中简要提到过，但是
a lot of those took far more implementation effort than we'd expected
很多工作的实施努力超出了我们的预期。
to access lower layers in the protocol stack or to modify the media formats and
访问协议栈中的较低层或修改媒体格式和
protocols that are intertwined and increasingly complex ways.
访问协议栈中的较低层或修改媒体格式和协议，它们以交织且日益复杂的方式存在。
Bacon assumptions and certainly to start testing things in larger AR platforms and
培根的假设无疑是为了开始在更大的AR平台上测试事物。
game engines that are in, and
游戏引擎本身就是 значительные программные инженерные проекты.
of themselves significant software engineering projects.
游戏引擎本身就是重大的软件工程项目。
So there was a lot, I think that we learned about how to potentially
所以有很多东西，我认为我们学到了一些关于如何可能地
support this kind of experimentation a little better in the future and
支持这种实验在未来能够得到更好的支持，并且
maybe lobby a bit for more access to the hardware and
也许可以稍微游说一下，争取更多地访问硬件和
operating system functionality that's needed to really demo NDN's value.
也许可以稍微游说一下，争取更多地访问硬件和操作系统功能，这对于真正展示NDN价值是必要的。
So one of the common questions we got was well,
那么，我们常收到的一个问题是，嗯，
can't we use the same thing using IP?
我们能使用IP做同样的事情吗？
And there are a few answers here.
这里有一些答案。
I won't go into all of them, but this is a nice conversation that we might be able to
我不会详述所有的内容，但这是一个不错的对话，我们可能能够在接下来的几天里，在一些小组讨论中进行。
have in some of the panels over the course of the next several days.
在接下来的几天里，在一些小组讨论中进行。
But then to wrap up here with a little bit more on our sort of understanding
但是，为了在这里总结我们的理解，还需要进一步阐述一些内容。
is we were really looking for OS platforms to allow deeper access to the network.
我们确实在寻找能够更深入地访问网络的操作系统平台。
And so that's a place that we need to maybe provide some support for
所以那是我们可能需要提供一些支持的地方。
researchers.
研究人员。
Certainly we wanted to try to allow applications to implement a data centric
当然我们希望尝试允许应用程序实现以数据为中心的
paradigm directly in the application design,
范式直接应用于应用程序设计中，
which was something that the Indian CNL library tries to do.
这是印度CNL图书馆试图去做的事情。
And in cases where we can with that type of library to allow
在我们可以利用那种类型的图书馔的情况下允许
that data centric designed to also operate at the network level and
在网络层面也设计成以数据为中心的操作方式，并且
provides something where there's not maybe as much of a semantic gap between how
提供了一种方式，在这种方式中，可能没有那么大的语义差距，介于如何在应用设计师工作和NDN网络如何工作之间。
application designers are working, and how the NDN network works.
应用设计师的工作方式，以及NDN网络的工作原理。
And this is guiding us towards, hopefully some future fruitful areas of focus.
这正引导我们朝着，希望是一些未来富有成果的关注领域前进。
We're not trying to change everything all at once, but
我们并不是想要一次性改变所有事情，而是
work potentially bit by bit from the edge focusing on plug and play behavior.
我们希望逐渐地、一点一点地从边缘开始工作，专注于即插即用的行为。
the NDN platform and greenfields where a lot of this previous sort of
NDN平台和绿地在很大程度上是此前的这种情况
the previous emphasis and optimizations for IPR had less of a foothold.
之前对知识产权的重视和优化在很大程度上没有太大的立足点。
So some of the the future work is listed here and happy to talk about any of that.
因此，一些未来的工作在这里列出了，我很乐意讨论其中的任何内容。
>> Yeah, maybe I'll take one question if there is one.
是的，如果有问题的话，我可以回答一个。
If not, then maybe a final comment on the most exciting future work as you see it.
如果没有的话，那或许可以对你看来最令人兴奋的未来工作做一个最后的评论。
Is there a question out there?
有没有问题？
Thank you for a great presentation.
谢谢你精彩的演讲。
Okay, final thoughts on exciting future.
好的，关于激动人心的未来的最后想法。
>> I can tell you the final thought that's sort of the most exciting for
我可以告诉你最令人激动的最后想法是什么，那就是对于
me which is plug and play sounds simple or maybe simplistic, but
我可以告诉你最令人激动的最后想法是什么，那就是对于我来说，所谓的即插即用听起来很简单，或者可能过于简化，但是I think the more that we can take this experience in the last three years and
I think the more that we can take this experience in the last three years and
我认为我们越能够利用过去三年的经验，
at each within each thrust look at ways to get these tools into the hands of as
在每一个推进方向中，探索方法将这些工具交到尽可能多的研究人员和实验者手中。
many researchers and experimenters as possible.
将这些工具交到尽可能多的研究人员和实验者手中。
That seems to be one of the most exciting parts of the future work right now.
这似乎是当前未来工作中最令人兴奋的部分之一。
>> And with that, you're focusing on the ease of configurability, I think.
>> 正因为此，您关注的是配置的便利性，我认为。
>> Ease of configurability, but I think also trying to find ways to have
>> 正因为此，您关注的是配置的便利性，但我认为也在尝试找到方法以便
the API's present an easy to understand data centric perspective.
API 提供了易于理解的以数据为中心的视角。
So it's definitely making things work as simply as possible to experiment,
所以它肯定是尽可能简化事物，以便进行实验，
but also trying to kind of help guide applications to a data centric perspective
但也试图在某种程度上帮助引导应用程序转向以数据为中心的视角。
that allows them to take advantage of the network behavior underneath.
这使他们能够利用底层的网络行为。
>> Great, can the organisers tell us,
>> 太好了，组织者能告诉我们吗？
do we have time for one more question?
我们还有时间再问一个问题吗？
>> Don't think so leave.
>> 不要这么想就离开。
>> Okay, we'll take it offline.
>> 好的，我们私下里讨论。
>> Thank you so much.
>> 非常感谢您。
>> Thank you all.
>> 非常感谢大家。
>> Thank you very much.
非常感谢大家。
The agenda has the next panel two, but
议程上接下来是小组讨论二，但是
we have Ilya who missed the big recession and
我们有伊利亚，他错过了大衰退，
we will give him no more than ten minutes.
我们最多给他十分钟时间。
So we're delaying panel two no more than ten minutes, Ilya.
所以我们最多延迟第二个小组讨论十分钟，伊利亚。
>> Okay, great.
>> 好的，很好。
So yes, thank you for having me here today.
是的，感谢今天有我在此。
I think my presentation be somewhat out of maybe not quite in context with everything
我认为我的演讲或许有些脱离了上下文。
else that was discussed, because it's not specific to Indian architecture.
因为这不是专门针对印度建筑的，所以那些讨论的其他内容我可能没有涉及。
So fabric is a midscale research infrastructure.
所以织物是一种中等规模的研究基础设施。
Project funded last year before years to build a nationwide
去年资助的项目旨在建设一个全国性的
networking testbed that will allow experimentation with
去年资助的项目旨在建设一个全国性的网络测试平台，该平台将允许进行实验，以探索各种分布式的、垂直领域的应用和
a variety of distributed, verticals, applications and
多种分布式的、垂直领域的应用和
architectures with a key idea being that it is really kind of
架构的一个关键思想实际上是这样的，
time to look at potentially putting more state in the network.
是时候考虑在网络中加入更多的状态了。
And what form that state might take we as the builders of this
我们作为这个网络基础设施的构建者，应该考虑状态可能呈现的形式，尽量不要对...
infrastructure try not to have too much influence on,
我们作为这个网络基础设施的构建者，应该尽量不要对其产生过多影响，
rather just trying to create as many options there for experimenters to try.
我们只是尽量为实验者创造尽可能多的选项供他们尝试。
And of course, NDN architecture is one example of an open new
当然，NDN架构是一个开放的新型互联网架构示例，它具有更多需要存储和维护状态的特性。
internet architecture that has more state that requires storage and
需要存储和维护状态的互联网架构
processing capabilities out of the network.
需要将处理能力从网络中分离出来。
But as I said, we ourselves as the builders of this infrastructure,
但正如我所说，我们作为这些基础设施的构建者，
try to remain neutral to the various possibilities.
努力对各种可能性保持中立。
That should the computing community has a chance to explore
计算机界应该有机会去探索
these various inflection points in the architecture and
这些在架构中的各种拐点和
then decide what works and what doesn't at a reasonable level of scale.
然后在一个合理的规模水平上决定什么有效，什么无效。
So, just to briefly introduce the leadership team has myself and
因此，简单介绍一下领导团队，包括我自己和
Nita Nicolaj from inner cylinder Urbana Champaign in the manga is the executive
Nita Nicolaj 来自内圆柱 Urbana Champaign，在漫画中是执行主任。
director of Department of Energy's energy sciences network.
美国能源部能源科学网络的主任。
Jim Griffin from University of Kentucky, Casey Wang from Clemson.
Jim Griffin来自肯塔基大学，Casey Wang来自克莱姆森大学。
Tom layman, also Polo Roof and Zong Ling, Fei.
汤姆·莱曼，还有波罗·鲁夫和宗灵，飞。
So what is fabric?
那么什么是fabric？
As I mentioned, its goal to enable a new paradigm for
正如我所提到的，它的目标是为了使一种新的范式成为可能。
distributed protocols, applications and architectures.
分布式协议、应用程序和架构。
The intent is to build a nationwide programmable network
旨在构建一个全国范围的可编程网络。
with significant compute storage capabilities at each node within the core,
具有在核心的每个节点内的重要计算存储能力，
not just at the edge, but in the core.
不仅仅在边缘，而且在核心。
Such that you have a continuum now of possibilities of where to put your storage
这样你现在就有了一个连续的可能性范围，用来决定在哪里放置你的存储设备。
computation on data as it travels through the network.
在数据通过网络传输时进行计算。
And the idea is that the computation can be supported by a variety of augmented
计算可以由多种增强的计算设备支持，比如GPU、FPGA、网络处理器等等。
computing devices like GPU like FPGAs, network processors, etc etc.
计算设备如GPU、FPGA、网络处理器等等。
Quality of Service is important from repeatability, reproducibility of
服务质量从可重复性、可再现性的角度来看是非常重要的。
experience point of view, we shouldn't forget that this is a testbed, so
从经验的角度来看，我们不应该忘记这是一个实验平台，所以
that's provided by dedicated hundred gigabit optical links.
这是通过专用的百吉比光纤链接提供的。
And then also the ideas of fabric is not in itself a sandbox, but
而且布料的概念本身并不是沙盒，但是
rather in connects incentives to interconnect other facilities HPC
而且它将激励措施与连接其他设施的高性能计算(HPC)联系起来。
centers cloud wireless test bits Public clouds, commercial clouds and
公共云、商业云以及
a number of edge nodes such that the experimenter can pick what her
一些边缘节点，以便实验者可以选择什么样的资源是在她的全球实验范围内，
kind of selection of resources is within her global experiment and
可以选择哪些资源是在她的全球实验范围内，
you know, pick the ones that are closest to what what she needs.
你知道的，选择那些最接近她所需的资源。
Rather than having to kind of reinvent everything from scratch because fabric
因为纺织品，我们没有必要从头开始重新发明一切。
really can't and shouldn't try to reproduce the entirety of the ecosystem of
我们真的不能也不应该尝试复制整个生态系统的完整性。
computation on other resources available to researchers today.
它在今天研究人员可用的其他资源上进行计算。
Instead it's producing.
它正在产生。
It provides a separate way of transporting data between those
它提供了一种在它们之间传输数据的独立方式
while computing on it in flight, essentially.
在飞行中进行计算的过程，基本上就是这样。
This is our idea of what the topology will look like when it's completed.
这是我们对于拓扑结构完成时的样子的设想。
Of course, subject to change over the next few years.
当然，这在接下来的几年里可能会有所改变。
We're at the end of year one of the four year construction project.
我们现在正处于为期四年的建设项目的第一年末尾。
All the blue links are dedicated hundred gig capacity.
所有蓝色链接都是专用的百吉比特容量。
And then the yellow is what we call this terabit super core.
然后黄色的部分是我们所说的太比特超级核心。
This is where we plan to have some version of a terabit network
这是我们计划建立某种形式的太比特网络的地方。
either it's one terabit 1.2 terabit per second.
无论是一太比特还是每秒1.2太比特。
Of course, there are locations where we will appear with public clouds using
当然，有些地方我们会使用公共云出现在
internet to Cloud Connect system.
互联网到云连接系统。
Such that, you can't really think of an experiment and
因此，你真的无法想象一个实验并且
infrastructure today that doesn't include some version of a public cloud.
因此，你真的无法想象一个实验并且不包含某种形式的公共云的基础设施。So obviously that's that's a requirement and
So obviously that's that's a requirement and
所以很明显，这是一个要求，
then you can see also all the facilities, at least the initial list of facilities,
那么你也可以看到所有的设施，至少是设施的初步清单，
we're going to connect Do you see tag cloud love powder cosmos,
我们将会连接，你看到了标签云、爱情粉末、宇宙吗？
the Pittsburgh supercomputing center mgh, PCC, etc, etc.
匹兹堡超级计算中心，MGH，PCC等等。
A little bit about the hardware.
关于硬件方面的一些信息。
So the whole idea is that we want to interpose compute and
所以整个想法是我们想要在计算之间插入一些东西。
storage, different types of compute and
存储、不同类型的计算和
storage into the path of fast packet flows that are right in the network.
存储进入网络中快速数据包流动的路径。
So, you know, each site is a rack of high performance servers,
所以，你知道，每个站点都是一组高性能服务器，
dual dual CPU 32 core, have half a terabyte
双双CPU 32核心，拥有半个TB的RAM，各站点的服务器有不同的配置。
of RAM, different flavors of servers in each site.
的RAM，每个站点的服务器配置各不相同。
Some have loaded with GPUs, some of FPGAs and network cards.
有些配备了GPU，有些配备了FPGA和网络卡。
Storage of different tiers on
不同层次的存储设施包括
some experimental provisional NVMe drives as well as rotating storage at each site.
一些实验性的临时NVMe驱动器以及每个站点的旋转存储设施。
And of course, everything connecting with to a to a to a switch that has
以及当然，一切都连接到了一个交换机上，该交换机具有
different types of Port speeds from 25 to 100 and above.
不同类型的端口速度从25到100及以上。
Gigabits per second.
千兆比特每秒。
FPGAs with support for P4, as is another goal and then mellanox Connect X-5 and
支持P4的FPGA是另一个目标，然后是Mellanox ConnectX-5 和
6 family cards as kind of hardware offload cards with OBS and things like that.
支持OBS等功能的6系列家族卡作为硬件卸载卡。
And then the idea is that the experimenter essentially gets access to these devices.
然后，这个想法是实验者本质上能够访问这些设备。
Primarily the mode we envision is using virtual machines with direct
我们主要设想的模式是使用具有直通功能的虚拟机。
attached PCI devices for some high value experiments, we can see
为了一些高价值实验，我们可以看到附加了PCI设备，
dedicating entire servers to those and provisioning them for that experiment.
为了这些高价值实验，我们专门为它们提供了整个服务器，并为实验进行了配置。
However, given the kind of the size of the facility,
然而，考虑到设施的规模大小，
the amount of resources at each site,
考虑到每个地点的资源数量，
we think that In order to make this a kind of successful multi user facility, we have
我们认为，为了使这成为一种成功的多用户设施，我们必须
to rely on some level of virtualization to achieve a level of scale.
为了实现一定规模的扩展，我们必须依赖于某种程度的虚拟化技术。
A typical experiment in fabric, this is absolutely unrealistic but
为了在织物中进行一个典型的实验，这完全是不现实的，但
it just sort of shows some of the ideas as purposely Showing on top of a map of
它只是在某种程度上展示了一些故意在地图上方显示的想法，
the United States just to show the level of this distributed capacity or,
美国仅仅是为了展示这种分布式能力的水平，或者说，
you might connect some external resource like, a cluster attack or SDSC, for
您可能会连接一些外部资源，比如集群攻击或SDSC，用于
instance, and then maybe you're sampling traffic that's going through this link.
例如，然后你可能会抽样监测通过这个链接的流量。
And you're using an SSD like an NVMe drive and
你正在使用像NVMe驱动器这样的SSD，并且
an FPGA to do some additional processing on the data and
使用FPGA对数据进行一些额外处理，并且
it's usually it's it's like a bump in fiber or bump on wire.
它通常就像是光纤或电线上的一个凸起。
Then maybe you want to build a virtual switch out of these different
那么或许你想要用这些不同的设备来构建一个虚拟交换机。
network cards, some of them perhaps.
网络卡，或许有些是这样的。
With the four capabilities, some of them just kind of OBS, or
With the four capabilities, some of them may just be kind of obvious, or
maybe you're hosting an application within the network that uses GPUs, and again,
也许你在网络中托管了一个应用程序，它使用了GPU，再次，
maybe fast drives for caching data, things like that.
也许是用于缓存数据的快速驱动器之类的东西。
And we also have room for a small number of dedicated p for
和我们还有空间放置少量的专用p用于~!@#$%^&*()
switches if you really want very, very high port counts for density.
如果你真的需要非常非常高的端口数量来提高密度，可以使用交换机。
Comparatively high port density in a few locations, you could also do that.
在少数几个地方，你也可以实现相对较高的端口密度。
Yeah, this was kind of a conceptual idea of what a fabric now it looks like.
是的，这是对现在所谓的网络基础设施的一个概念性描述。
There's a head node or
~!@#$%^&*()
something that will workers equipped with different flavours of these PCI devices.
这将为工人配备具有不同类型的PCI设备。
two switches management switch for external access one data plane switch for
两个交换机：一个管理交换机用于外部访问，一个数据平面交换机用于
accessing the actual topology that you create As an experimenter,
访问您作为实验者创建的实际拓扑结构
just some of the examples of the use cases that that
这只是一些使用案例的例子，这些案例
might be useful particularly to this community, right?
可能特别对这个社区有用，对吧？
So with NDN wanting to do storage and processing of data in the network.
所以随着NDN想要在网络中进行数据存储和处理。
This is kind of part and parcel here of the architecture for
这是架构中不可或缺的一部分。
fabric You can do sort of direct pass through just the switch.
你可以通过交换机直接进行传递。
If you just want to bypass the site, you can pop the traffic into the site and
如果你只是想绕过网站，你可以将流量直接弹入网站中并且在站点存储中进行一些处理或者即时处理。
do some processing within the site storage or processing on the fly.
在站点存储中进行一些处理或者即时处理。
You can host the entire application and again have avid serve.
您可以托管整个应用程序，并再次让Avid服务器提供服务。
Packet flows coming in from multiple points.
多个点传入的数据包流。
So line rate stateful.
所以是按行速率有状态的。
And again, we don't know dictate what the state represents so within this case.
同样，我们并不清楚这个状态所代表的含义，所以在这种情况下。
It could be the data caches, it could be some control plane state,
它可能是数据缓存，也可能是某种控制平面状态，
some combination of the two.
它可能是这两者的某种结合。
That's up to the experimenter to decide.
这取决于实验者来决定。
We're also paying a lot of attention to measurement capabilities.
我们也非常关注测量能力。
So, each site likely was going to have a just GPS discipline clock for PTP.
因此，每个站点很可能会有一个仅用于PTP的GPS授时钟。
But so that you can take kind of
但这样你就可以进行某种
Packet Tracer spec of snapshots across the network with millisecond accuracy.
Packet Tracer 可以以毫秒级精度捕获网络中的快照。
And have some idea of what's going through the network.
并且对网络中传输的内容有所了解。
Now obviously, it's very high packet rates like hundred gigabits per second,
显然，这是非常高的数据包传输速率，比如每秒百吉比特，
you won't be able to hold a whole lot of traffic in these.
这些设备无法处理大量的流量。
But nonetheless, it's a possibility that it opens up to do this.
但尽管如此，它确实为此打开了一种可能性。
We will have smart videos as well as the server's themselves instrumented for
我们将对智能视频以及服务器本身进行仪器化处理，用于
measuring power consumption.
我们将对智能视频以及服务器本身进行仪器化处理，用于测量功耗。Some optical layer measurements were available, now this facility will not have.
Some optical layer measurements were available, now this facility will not have
过去这个设施可以进行一些光层测量，但现在不再拥有这种功能。
an edge optical layer, that's not part of the architecture.
边缘光层，并不是架构的一部分。
However, some level of measurements from the optical layer should be available.
然而，光层应该提供某种程度的测量数据。
And of course, the traditional utilization measures from CPU, memory,
当然，还有来自CPU、内存的传统利用率度量指标，
disk etc, for their accounts.
磁盘等，用于他们的账户。
Port mirroring will be supported as well, so
端口镜像也将得到支持，所以
that you can capture certain flows if you want.
你可以捕获特定的流量，如果你想的话。
And I think that's it.
我认为就是这样了。
I wanted to keep it short and perhaps leave a little bit of room for
我想保持简短，或许留一点空间给
questions instead.
其他的问题。
I'm gonna stop sharing maybe for now and wait for questions.
我现在可能会停止分享，等待问题。
There's a question of how users conduct experiments, can you hear me?
用户如何进行实验，这是一个问题，你能听到我说话吗？
Can you hear me okay?
你能听清楚我说话吗？
>> Yes, we heard you.
>> 是的，我们听到你说的了。
>> Yeah, so, the users define the topology of what they want to do,
是的，用户定义了他们想要做的拓扑结构，
they define the properties of that topology,
他们定义了该拓扑结构的属性，
they define the elements of the topology in the configuration.
他们在配置中定义了拓扑结构的元素。
Essentially, it's either going through the portal or using the API's.
本质上，它要么通过门户进行操作，要么使用API。
The user interface is going to,
用户界面将要，
a primary user interface is likely to be through Jupiter notebooks.
主要的用户界面很可能是通过Jupyter笔记本来实现的。
So that you have a programmable kind of scriptable environment where you can
以便你有一个可编程的、可脚本化的环境，在这里你可以
launch your experiments, configure it, collect data,
启动你的实验，配置它，收集数据，
process data and then hopefully get the results you're looking for the.
处理数据，然后希望得到你期望的结果。
So this gonna rely on federated identity.
所以这将依赖于联合身份认证。
So the researchers from the US institutions are part of in common
所以来自美国机构的研究人员是InCommon的一部分。
federation should have no trouble accessing this.
联盟应该可以轻松访问这个。
By the time we're done with the construction, we will have an AUP, as well
到我们完成建设时，我们也将拥有一份可接受使用政策（AUP），以及其他政策来帮助理解如何在不久的将来最好地使用设施。
as other policies to help understand how best to use facility in the near future.
以及其他政策来帮助理解如何在不久的将来最好地使用设施。
And we're planning to open up a facility to early experimenters in the summer of
我们计划在夏季向早期实验者开放一个设施。
2021.
2021.
It's going to be more of a kind of a first come first serve.
这将主要是一种先到先得的方式。
We will be working with some members of the research community to kinda help us
我们将与研究界的一些成员合作，以便在某种程度上帮助我们。
come in and kick the tires on the facility,
进来试试这个设施的性能。
figure out what works, what doesn't, what can work better.
搞清楚什么有效，什么无效，什么可以做得更好。
So the answer is no, this is a construction project,
所以答案是否定的，这是一个建设项目，
we've only completed the first year as I just mentioned,
我们刚刚完成了第一年，正如我刚才提到的，
the general availability is 2023, limited availability is next year 2021.
总体可用性是2023年，有限的可用性是明年2021年。
So how we can calculate participate in the fabric?
那么我们如何才能参与到这个结构中呢？
So the first thing I would encourage you to do is to visit our website.
所以我首先建议你做的就是访问我们的网站。
What is fabric.net?
fabric.net是什么？
What is fabric.net, there is a button there, you can click get involved and
fabric.net是什么？那里有一个按钮，你可以点击参与进来。
you will get monthly or periodic anyways mailers as to what's going on.
您将会定期或每月收到邮件，了解最新动态。
We are hosting a number of workshops with different members of different
我们正在举办一系列与不同社区的不同成员合作的研讨会，
communities, trying to collect more requirements, ideas for experiments,
社区，试图收集更多的需求、实验的想法，
tools that could be useful to other experimenters.
可以对其他实验者有用的工具。
One of the things that we have in mind is being able to stand up kind of an on
我们考虑的一件事是能够建立一种临时的
demand NDN profile experiment within fabric such that.
我们需要在网络中进行NDN配置文件实验。
People who want to use NDN kind of out of the box can just kind of press the button
想要直接使用NDN的人可以简单地按下按钮。
and launch in NDN network of the size that they want across the country.
并在全国范围内按照他们想要的规模启动NDN网络。
So that idea of an experiment profile is pretty integral to our thinking.
因此，实验配置文件的概念对我们的思考至关重要。
Yes, the idea of fabric is that you have dedicated resources.
是的，fabric的概念是你拥有专用资源。
The question was, would the experimenters have dedicated resources if necessary?
实验者如有必要，是否会拥有专用资源？
Yes, the whole idea is that you reserve the resources that you need, and
是的，整个想法是你预留你需要的资源，以及
we either tell you sorry we're not available help you with a calendar.
我们只能说抱歉，我们无法帮助你管理日程安排。
Schedule your experiment in the future or
安排你将来的实验或者
provide your resources right away if they're available.
如果你的资源现成可用，请立即提供。
But reproducibility which, reproducibility is the driver here,
但可重现性才是这里的驱动因素，可重现性才是关键。
but in order to get the reproducibility, you have to have dedicated resources.
但为了获得可重现性，你必须拥有专用资源。
Usually reserved for your use.
通常为您专用保留。
Fabric will also offer a shared layer three capacity for
Fabric还将提供一个共享的三层容量用于
those types of experiments where perhaps current IP
这些实验类型或许是目前的IP
implementation is enough to move the data around.
实现足以进行数据传输。
But the experimenter might be just interested
但实验者可能只是感兴趣
in experimenting with higher level concepts and applications and
在实验更高层次的概念和应用时，
they don't really want to rule the whole entire architecture or protocol stack.
他们并不真的想要控制整个架构或协议栈。
Or they just wanna experiment with applications, but in addition to that,
或者他们只是想尝试一些应用程序，但除此之外，
to that layer three default kind of best effort layer three,
到那个三层默认的尽力而为的三层，
there will be dedicated capacity that will be reservable across the entire footprint.
将会有专门的容量可以在整个足迹范围内预留。
We also have an extension now, plans extension to Europe and Japan.
我们现在也有了扩展，计划扩展到欧洲和日本。
So United Kingdom, Bristol,
所以英国，布里斯托，
the Netherlands Interserve Amsterdam, Switzerland CERN,
荷兰 Interserve 阿姆斯特丹，瑞士欧洲核子研究中心（CERN），
Interserve Tokyo, we will have sites there as well.
Interserve 东京，我们也将在那里设立站点。
>> Okay, I guess we're getting ready for the IoT and edge applications panel.
好的，我想我们正在为物联网和边缘应用小组讨论做准备。
Maybe all the panelists can start to get ready.
也许所有的小组成员都可以开始准备了。
And I wanted to kind of start out just saying,
我想首先说，
what distinguishes edge applications.
区分边缘应用程序的特点是什么。
And it's nice that we had this earlier session where
我们很高兴能在早些时候进行这场会议，
we had people speaking about different edge applications.
我们有人讲述了不同的边缘应用程序。
And we had that morning session, which was sort of the opposite and
我们还有那个上午的会议，可以说是与之相反的情况，
those applications made heavy use of caching and storage and
这些应用程序大量使用了缓存和存储，以及
movement of persistent data.
这些应用程序大量使用了缓存和存储，以及持久数据的移动。
And I think that in contrast to Ed's application is kind
与Ed的应用相比，我认为这种做法是出于善意的。
of focus on using NDN as a communication protocol and
专注于使用NDN作为通信协议。
the data could be more affirmable although still maybe durable.
数据可能更加可靠，尽管可能依旧耐用。
And it makes really heavy use of security so that in the automotive applications and
并且它非常重视安全性，以便在汽车应用中能够
really exploit that broadcast nature of the edge networks.
确实能够充分利用边缘网络的广播特性。
And that was something that Jeff mentioned in his talk.
而这正是杰夫在他的演讲中提到的一个问题。
And I think it was particularly interesting how the Intel
而我认为英特尔公司如何特别有趣。
person kind of set this up for us.
这个人为我们安排好了这一切。
And I think that NDN as a NSF project really did get
这个作为NSF项目的NDN确实得到了
started not looking at the edge because it was a future internet application.
开始之时并未关注边缘，因为它是一种未来互联网应用。
But it's interesting to note that the roots of this and
但有趣的是，这一切的根源和
the new way to look at networking and some of the early work at
这种新的网络观点以及一些早期的工作
PARC really was focused on things you could do with the edge.
PARC 真的非常关注你可以在网络边缘做的事情。
And when you do that, you don't have to worry so much about IP routing and
当你这样做的时候，你就不需要过分担心IP路由和
other elements of the infrastructure that we already have, and
我们已经拥有的其他基础设施要素，以及
you can solve that problem at the edge with NDN style communications.
你可以通过NDN风格的通信在边缘解决那个问题。
So what we're gonna do here is I'm going to have these
所以我们要做的是我会让这些
four excellent panelists speak too.
所以我们要做的是我会让这四位出色的小组成员也发言。We'll do it in the order of Justin Caswell,
We'll do it in the order of Justin Caswell,
我们将按照Justin Caswell的顺序来进行，
then Dan Massey, then and then Dang Hu.
然后是Dan Massey，接着是Dang Hu。
And I wanna start with Justin.
然后我想从Justin开始。
And what, I wanted to introduce Justin,
然后我想介绍Justin，
but I lost that, my introduction.
但我丢失了那个，我的介绍。
I hope they get it.
我希望他们能明白。
Okay, I do not have it anymore.
好的，我已经没有了。
Okay, well hang on a second.
好的，稍等一下。
[LAUGH] All right, so Justin is the founder and CEO of Rakhine,
好的，所以Justin是Rakhine的创始人和CEO，
which is a company that focuses on blockchain network solutions for
他是一家专注于区块链网络解决方案的公司的创始人兼首席执行官，该公司服务于电信行业。
the telecommunications industry.
他服务于电信行业。
He's had 20 plus years and communication systems with a focus on wireless for
他在通信系统方面拥有20多年的经验，专注于无线通讯。
both terrestrial and satellite.
无线和卫星通信。
And that includes companies like ExxonMobil and FedEx.
这包括了像埃克森美孚和联邦快递这样的公司。
Justin is a serial entrepreneur, a full stack developer and an innovative leader.
贾斯汀是一位连续创业者、全栈开发者和创新领导者。
He works directly with network operators, data centers, governments and
他直接与网络运营商、数据中心、政府以及
private industry in cutting edge technology operations.
他的工作特别聚焦于5G网络内的尖端技术运营私营行业。
His work has a specific focus within 5G networks,
他的工作特别聚焦于5G网络内，
advanced communication systems, leveraging AI and of course, NDN.
他的工作特别聚焦于5G网络内，高级通信系统的应用，利用人工智能，当然还有NDN。So, Justin, do you wanna go ahead and
So, Justin, do you wanna go ahead and
那么，贾斯汀，你想继续并且
explain to us some of the issues that you see and
解释一下你所看到的一些问题并且
things that will be interesting to the audience?
解释一下你所看到的一些问题并且对观众来说会有趣的事情？Thanks.
Thanks.
谢谢。
>> Thanks, Kathy for the introduction, yeah, so
谢谢你的介绍，Kathy，是的，所以
some of the things we're working on.
我们正在研究的一些事情。
So just right out of the gate, I think what our involvement was with NDN is we
我们一开始接触NDN时，我们所参与的是
wanted to use a blockchain application running on top of NDN.
我们想要使用一个运行在NDN之上的区块链应用程序。
Because there's [LAUGH] a lot of efficiencies you can you can
因为有很多效率，你可以你可以~!@#$%^&*()
glean from just that.
从那里就能收集到信息。
But then we we moved into a little bit more of the core network operations and
但随后我们深入到了核心网络运营的更多方面。
we started looking at saying, okay, well, how can we apply NDN in a 5G deployment or
我们开始考虑，好的，那我们如何将NDN应用于5G部署中呢？
any kind of modern wireless network deployment really?
任何类型的现代无线网络部署，是吗？
So we kind of started dialing in on the IoT aspects,
因此，我们开始专注于物联网方面的事务。
the challenges wrapped around encryption, bringing that in through your gateway.
加密带来的挑战，将其通过网关引入。
Lots of proprietary gateways and
许多专有网关和
hardware out there that you have to overcome, so a lot of challenges there.
有很多需要克服的硬件问题，所以存在很多挑战。
I think if we can work a little bit more with OEMs and get NDN integrated
我认为如果我们能与原始设备制造商（OEM）进一步合作，并将NDN集成进设备中，我认为那将是一个重大的进步。
directly into devices, I think that would be a substantial step forward.
如果我们能直接将NDN集成进设备中，我认为那将是一个重大的进步。
In addition to that, I think if we could get NDN,
除此之外，我认为如果我们能够得到NDN，
working directly in the gateways for those devices.
直接在那些设备的网关中工作。
That's another substantial challenge,
这是另一个重大挑战，
that I think that would bring a lot to the industry.
我认为那将会为行业带来很多好处。
Some of the other things that we started looking at moving away from just IoT, but
我们开始关注的其他一些事情，不仅仅是物联网，而是转向...
really looking at broad compute platforms, right?
我们真的在关注广泛的计算平台，对吧？
So how do you take all of these things at the edge, whether that's IoT devices or
那么你如何处理所有这些边缘设备，无论是物联网设备还是
you're taking autonomous vehicles, or UAV's or Smart Cities.
你正在处理的是无人驾驶汽车、无人航空器或智慧城市。
So there's a ton of data that you need to ingest, especially,
所以有大量的数据需要你处理，尤其是，
whenever you start looking at 5G deployments.
所以当你开始研究5G部署时。
So whenever you say, all right, we've got all these devices.
所以，当你说好的，我们有这么多设备的时候。
We've got all these users just machine to machine,
我们有所有这些用户，仅仅是机器对机器，
some of its actual users to users.
它的一些实际用户对用户来说。
And you've got all these different dynamic sets of information that you're
和你有所有这些不同的动态信息集合在你手中。
pulling in.
吸引进来。
Now, you're not only having to deal with the baseband processing of that, right?
现在，你不仅要处理基带处理，对吧？
But now,
但现在，
you have to take these these applications that are running on that 5G network.
您需要管理这些运行在5G网络上的应用程序。
And then now, you have to say, okay, well, how are we gonna get it pushed through and
然后现在，你得说，好的，我们要怎样才能推进这件事呢？
actually meet the requirements of the low latency that 5G kind of requires?
实际上是否能够满足5G所要求的低延迟需求呢？
So looking at that, we were working on an edge based solution.
所以看这个情况，我们正在研究一个基于边缘计算的解决方案。
It's a mobile edge compute platform that integrates NDN in the middle of
它是一个集成了中间NDN的移动边缘计算平台。
the technology stack.
技术栈。
So we're using Mellanox NIC's programmable NIC's kind of under the network side.
所以我们在网络方面使用了Mellanox NIC的可编程网卡。
So we're just layering that in, and
所以我们正在逐层加入这一功能，以及
then we're using sub-frameworks to build out some intelligent routing platforms.
因此我们正在使用子框架来构建一些智能路由平台。
And we're just leveraging some AI and some other existing frameworks that are out
我们正在利用一些人工智能技术和其他现有的框架。
there currently, but we're going to be expanding on those.
目前我们就是这样，但我们将会在这些基础上进行扩展。
And so what we'll actually do is combine the baseband processing.
我们实际上会做的是结合基带处理。
We put NDN in the middle, right, and
我们将NDN放在中间，对，然后
then we can push the the next the Mellanox NIC's down below.
然后我们可以将下一个Mellanox网卡推到下面。
And what that's allowing us to do theoretically, we haven't proven this yet,
这在理论上允许我们去做一些事情，但我们还没有证明这一点，
but what we're hoping to prove right, is that now we can intelligently move
但我们希望能够证明的是，现在我们可以智能地移动数据，无论是跨RAND，还是从边缘或本地数据中心。
data across the RAND, or from edge or local data centers.
跨RAND或从边缘或本地数据中心移动数据。
Back out to these edge compute platforms and so
返回这些边缘计算平台，因此
we're looking at an efficiency level for for routing.
我们正在考察路由的效率水平。
But what we're also really considering here is having a data aware
但我们在这里真正考虑的也是拥有一个数据感知的
platform where now, you can deploy these these edge based applications.
平台，在这里，您现在可以部署这些基于边缘的应用程序。
Would typically normally run at like a public cloud level.
通常会在类似公共云层级上运行。
And so now, if you can push that out onto this mobile edge compute platform that can
然后将其推送到这个移动边缘计算平台上，该平台通常会在类似公共云层级上运行，接着再与一个5G无线网络连接起来。
then be tied into a 5G wireless network.
然后再与一个5G无线网络连接起来。
It doesn't have to be a 5G wireless network, but obviously,
它不一定要是一个5G无线网络，但显然，
you get a lot of benefits if you if it's tied in there.
如果它与此相关联，你将会获得许多好处。
And so the idea right is that now you can have operators running their
那么这个想法，对吧，是现在你可以让操作员在这个计算平台上运行他们的应用程序。
applications on this compute platform.
在这个计算平台上的应用程序。
You can have developers running application on this compute platform.
您可以让开发者在这个计算平台上运行应用程序。
But you're also really getting a lot of network efficiencies on both
但您也确实在两端都获得了很多网络效率。
the RAND side, and then your hardline network side.
在RAND一侧，以及您的硬线网络一侧。
And so those are kind of the main things that we're looking at,
所以这些是我们主要关注的事项。
we've got a lot of interest on on those.
我们对那些项目有很大的兴趣。
We're doing some test beds here in the United States, down in Texas, and
我们在美国这里，特别是德克萨斯州，正在做一些试验基地，还有
then also in a couple of other countries,
然后还在其他几个国家，
where they're interested in this type of a solution.
他们对这种解决方案感兴趣的地方。
That being said, we're also launching some of our own applications on that mobile
也就是说，我们还将在该移动平台上推出一些自己的应用程序。
edge compute platform.
边缘计算平台。
And so that's tying it to more of like a gaming use case,
因此，这更多地将其与游戏用例联系起来，
just working with kind of NVIDIA and some others in that room.
因此，这更多地将其与游戏用例联系起来，我们正在与NVIDIA以及该领域的其他一些公司合作。So we've got some pretty substantial challenges on our side.
So we've got some pretty substantial challenges on our side.
因此，我们这边面临着一些相当大的挑战。
Everything is pretty new right now, we're still figuring out a lot of the the 5G
目前一切都很新，我们还在摸索很多关于5G的事情。
infrastructure build out and deployments.
基础设施建设和部署。
Especially, whenever you look,
尤其是，无论你何时看向。
just at the global kind of 5G evolution that's going on.
就在全球正在进行的5G演变之中。
But we believe that where the real unlocking potential is at the edge.
但我们相信真正的潜力释放是在边缘计算上。
We feel the networks will come up to par, right,
我们认为网络性能将达到标准。
through the evolution of 5G on the wireless side.
通过无线端5G的发展演变。
And then the data centers,
然后是数据中心，
and the networks themselves there, we also feel are gonna be upgraded as
接着是网络本身，我们也认为这些网络将会在未来几年得到升级，以满足5G的需求。
well over the coming years to meet those demands of the 5G.
在未来几年中，以满足5G的需求，我们将大幅度地升级这些设施。
And so sitting at the edge with a mobile edge compute platform that
在未来几年中，以满足5G的需求，我们将大幅度地升级这些设施。因此，坐在边缘上，配备了移动边缘计算平台的我们，可以直接交付支持NDN的产品。
delivers NDN out of the box.
直接交付支持NDN的产品。
Is our goal and I think that's our first step and
我们的目标，我认为那是我们的第一步，
really trying to commercialize NDN at least from our optics, right?
我们确实在尝试从我们的视角来商业化NDN，对吧？
And then applying the the NDN blockchain application solution on top of that
再在此基础上应用NDN区块链应用解决方案。
to bring in some more automation if you will, so we can validate data flows.
为了引入更多的自动化，我们可以验证数据流。
Now, you can validate analytics, immutable records for audits, and tracing and
现在，您可以验证分析数据、不可变的审计记录以及追踪和……各种不同的事物。
all kinds of different things.
各种不同的事物。
So that's really where we sit, we've got a lot of challenges like I said,
所以这确实是我们所处的位置，就像我说的，我们面临着许多挑战，
ahead of us.
在我们面前。
But we're getting more and more interest from industry, both in the telecom side.
但我们越来越多地获得了工业界的兴趣，包括电信领域。
But then also private industry for hardware and software applications.
但同时也包括硬件和软件应用的私营产业。
>> Okay, thanks, Justin, let's go through everybody, and
好的，谢谢你，贾斯汀，我们来看看每个人，然后
then we'll take some questions at the end or you can even question each other.
然后我们将在最后提出一些问题，或者你们甚至可以互相提问。
So next up is Dan Massey and Dan is the program lead to
接下来是Dan Massey，Dan是项目负责人，负责...
the operate through portion of the DODs 5G to next G initiatives.
他曾是科罗拉多博尔德分校的一名教员，并参与了国防部从5G到下一代技术（next G）倡议的运作部分。
He was previously a faculty member at Colorado Boulder and
participated in the operational aspects of the Department of Defense's initiative from 5G to the next generation technology (next G).
program manager for the Cyber Security Division Science and
项目经理，负责网络安全部门科学与……
Technology directorate, that's the CST.
技术总监，那就是CST。
Yeah, and in the Department of Homeland Security as a CSP program manager,
是的，在国土安全部担任CSP项目经理，
he developed and manage programs where researchers from both academics and
他开发并管理了一个项目，在该项目中，学术界和工业界的研究人员能够识别、解决并部署网络安全解决方案，以应对来自
industry, identify, address and deploy cyber security solutions that
行业界的研究人员能够识别、解决并部署网络安全解决方案，以应对来自
improves the security and resilience of the Internet.
提高了互联网的安全性和弹性。
And Dan was one of the original NSF FIA NDN project.
丹是最初的NSF FIA NDN项目的成员之一。
Okay, Dan.
好的，丹。
Great. Well, thank you.
非常好。谢谢你。
I really appreciate the opportunity to be here.
我非常感谢有机会来到这里。
And I've got some, I think interesting, new stuff to talk about.
我有一些我认为很有趣的新东西要谈。
So as Kathy was just pointing out,
所以正如凯西刚才指出的，
I've just come on board in the DODs, 5G, the next G initiative.
我刚刚加入了国防部的5G下一代通信技术倡议。
And so I'm the program manager for something called can operate through.
因此，我是一个名为“能够穿透操作”的项目经理。
And I wanted to kind of say a little bit about what that is and, why I think that's
我想稍微谈谈那是什么，以及我为什么认为那是
particularly relevant to NDN and why we should be talking about that here?
特别与NDN相关，以及我们为什么应该在这里讨论这个问题？
So as you guys already know, right, as already mentioned in
所以正如你们已经知道的，对吧，正如已经提到的在
Justin stock just a little bit is 5G is coming up pretty quick.
5G即将迅速到来。
It's giving us a lot of new opportunities.
它为我们提供了许多新的机会。
And so from the DOD side, we're very interested in how we can leverage that,
因此从国防部这边来说，我们非常感兴趣的是如何利用这一点，
and how we can do that without thinking in terms of the traditional model.
因此，我们如何在不局限于传统模式的思维中实现这一点。
Which I'll claim devolved from the good old Paul Baran multipaths
我将声称这源自于Paul Baran提出的多路径概念。
many ways to get there to what, but now is often more of a circuit
有许多方法可以达到目的，但现在通常更多的是一种环路连接，而我们太常依赖于这种方式。
based connection and all too often we've relied on that.
基于连接的方式，我们太常依赖于此。
As this community knows well the securing the channel rather than securing the data.
这个社区很清楚，与其保护数据，不如保护传输渠道。
That all goes away if we do it with 5G.
如果我们使用5G来实现，那么所有这些问题都将不复存在。
So in our vision of 5G in the operate through vision of 5G,
所以在我们对5G的愿景中，在5G的运作视角下，
we're gonna say we have to come and
我们得说我们必须来访并且
we have to operate through existing 5G networks that we don't operate.
我们必须通过我们不运营的现有5G网络来进行操作。
We don't trust, but we need to get sensitive,
我们不信任，但我们需要获取敏感的，
possibly even classified information across those networks.
我们可能需要在那些网络上获取甚至是机密的信息。
In an environment where I don't know what the network is,
在一个我不知道网络是什么的环境中，
I don't have the network equipment.
我没有网络设备。
The network equipment is manufactured by who knows who's operating it.
网络设备是由谁制造的，谁在操作它也不得而知。
And so can we operate through that kind of network?
我们能通过那种网络进行操作吗？
That's the SD idea and
这就是SD的想法，还有……
it fits here I think into the edge piece because a lot of this communication
它适合放在边缘部分，因为很多通信工作
in the 5G world especially, there's a lot of interesting stuff on the edge.
在5G世界中，尤其是边缘部分有很多有趣的东西。
Once I get that inside a secure DOD network, that's a different matter.
一旦我把它接入到一个安全的国防部网络，那就是另外一回事了。
But I've got all these things on the 5G network.
但是我已经把所有这些东西都接入到5G网络上了。
At the edge that are gonna need to communicate, they can be vehicles,
在边缘需要进行通信的可能是车辆，
this was discussed earlier.
这个问题之前已经讨论过了。
Earlier today there's a lot of interesting stuff for
今天早些时候有很多有趣的东西要讨论。
those vehicles are gonna be on on 5G networks.
这些车辆将会使用5G网络。
So how does that communication work?
那么这种通信是如何工作的呢？
And how do you do that securely in a zero trust environment?
在零信任环境中，如何安全地实现这一点呢？
And I'm gonna, and I think this group might have some answers to that.
所以我打算，我认为这个团队可能对此有一些答案。
So when we say zero trust, I wanna make a slight shift from the really good stuff,
所以当我们谈论零信任时，我想稍微转变一下对那些真正好的东西的看法，
thank you to NIST for hosting all this.
感谢NIST举办了这一切。
And NIST has some great documents out there on zero trust.
NIST已经发布了一些关于零信任的优秀文档。
We wanna take a slightly different spin on zero trust in that
我们想对零信任采取稍微不同的方法，即
often zero trust is focused on, I operate the network but
我们常常关注的是零信任，而我运营的网络却是...
I don't necessarily I don't want to build a wall around my network.
我不一定想要在我的网络周围建立一堵墙。
In our case, I wanna take zero trust a step further and
在我们的情况下，我想要进一步推进零信任模型。
so may even say this is already covered in the NIST documents and
有些人甚至可能会说，这已经在NIST文件中有所涵盖。
it maybe in this case, I don't even operate the network.
在这种情况下，我甚至不操作网络。
I'm just a user on the network.
我只是网络上的一个用户。
There's all these different paths, all these different knobs I can tune with 5G.
有这么多不同的路径，有这么多不同的调节旋钮可以用于5G。
And how do I do that, and somebody posted into, Dave ran posted in,
And how do I do that, and somebody posted into, Dave ran posted in,
do we care about traffic analysis absolutely, right.
我们当然非常关心流量分析，对吧。
In fact, I think that's one of our biggest interesting challenges.
实际上，我认为这是我们面临的最大的有趣挑战之一。
And so one thing that we've talked about a lot is, so,
实际上，我们讨论了很多的一个问题是，
when I talk about securely operating across an untrusted 5G network.
当我谈论在不受信任的5G网络上安全地进行操作时。
I'm gonna assume the data is encrypted.
我会假设数据是加密的。
I'm gonna assume that someone can exfiltrate the data but,
我会假设有人可以窃取数据，但是，
they can't break the encryption.
他们无法破解加密。
So I'm not too worried about, me sending a confidential
所以我并不太担心，我发送一条机密的
message to Justin encrypted with a appropriate cryptography
我发送给贾斯汀的信息使用了合适的加密技术进行了加密。
that we both share, so who is gonna to get access to that?
我们两个人共有的，那么谁将能够访问到那个？
But he's not gonna be able to decrypt it.
但他将无法解密它。
>> [LAUGH] I'm the bad guy.
>> [笑] 我是坏人。
>> Yeah.
是的。
We could set defense, we can kind of pick it up.
我们可以设立防御，我们可以尝试去理解它。
But what I am worried about is that traffic analysis.
但我担心的是流量分析。
The analogy we've been using is the pizza deliveries to the pentagon, right?
我们一直在用的比喻是披萨送到五角大楼，对吧？
So, the thought there is by sitting out at the pentagon sitting parking lot across
那么，这个想法是坐在五角大楼对面的停车场里。
the street from the pentagon and just counting food deliveries in and out.
就在五角大楼对面的街道上，只是数着进出的送餐数量。
You may be able to infer quite a bit about operational tempo, right.
你或许可以从中推断出相当多关于作战节奏的信息，对吧。
Friday night, a number of pizzas show up that could be Bob or
周五晚上，出现了许多可能是Bob点的披萨。
Alice's retirement party.
爱丽丝的退休派对。
That could be that means, people are working late and
这可能意味着，人们在加班并且……
there's some kind of hop going on.
可能正在进行某种跳跃。
So we're worried about that in this scenario,
所以我们担心的是在这种情况下，
which is can I operate through this network without revealing too much
所以我们担心的是在这种情况下，我是否可以通过这个网络操作而不暴露太多信息，and maybe there's a bunch of ways I could do that, but.
and maybe there's a bunch of ways I could do that, but.
也许有很多种方式可以做到这一点，但是。
But certainly traffic analysis volume metrics are of interest.
但毫无疑问，流量分析的体量指标是我们感兴趣的。
And we want to see how that can work.
我们想要了解这是如何实现的。
But even more so than on the confidentiality piece,
但比起保密性方面，我们更加关注的是
the availability piece is really the exciting part for us.
可用性方面确实是令我们感到兴奋的部分。
And so with all these different paths, how can I make this work, right.
要在这么多不同的路径中找到解决方案，这确实是个问题，对吧。
We can do dynamic spectrum allocations, right.
我们可以进行动态频谱分配，对吧。
So unlike our traditional wireless where we're on channel five or channel seven or
所以不像我们传统的无线通信，我们只能使用频道五或频道七或者
whatever, we can hop around 5G gives us the ability to hop around,
所以，我们可以在不同频道间跳转，5G赋予了我们这种在频道间跳转的能力，
it gives us all these other possibilities.
它为我们提供了所有这些其他的可能性。
It gives us the opportunity to relay but
它为我们提供了中继的机会，但是
I'll tell you that's really hard to do with a circuit, right.
我会告诉你，用电路来做这事确实很难。
There may be some other approach.
也许有一些其他的方法。
I don't know, maybe there's some other type of networking.
我不知道，也许有一些其他的网络类型。
I think, yeah.
我想，是的。
Could be about names or data or something instead of, but so
可能是关于名字或数据之类的，而不是其他的，但是如此
I think there could be some interesting things there.
我认为那里可能有一些有趣的东西。
So that's just sort of the big picture challenge.
所以那只是一个宏观上的挑战。
I wanted to, I wanted to paint is just to say, what
我想要，我想要画的只是想要说，什么
about 5G and what about specifically, availability and 5G and
关于5G，具体而言，是可用性和5G。
if I can get additional confidentiality and integrity in 5G, that's a bonus.
如果我能在5G中获得额外的保密性和完整性，那就是额外的好处。
But, but I think there's some interesting ways to look at that.
但是，但是我认为有一些有趣的方式来看待这个问题。
And you'll see last thing and then I'll pass it on to the next panel.
所以你会看到最后一件事，然后我会把它传递给下一个小组。
So you'll see three things coming out of this program.
所以你会看到这个程序产生三个结果。
It's a brand new program.
这是一个全新的程序。
So we've just added Professor Roy from the University of Washington,
所以我们刚刚邀请了华盛顿大学的罗伊教授，
who's a 5G expert.
他是一位5G专家。
So he's running something called Beyond 5G.
所以他在负责一个叫做“超越5G”的项目。
What do we do after 5G?
我们在5G之后该做什么？
Cuz 5G won't be the end.
因为5G不会是终点。
I'm running the operate through portion, which is to say, hey,
我正在执行操作过程部分，也就是说，嘿，
how do I operate on that existing 5G network?
我该如何在现有的5G网络上进行操作？
And there's a group that's currently out there called accelerate,
目前有一个名为accelerate的团体正在那里活动，
which is helping get this adoption into government systems.
它正在帮助将这种采用推广到政府系统中。
All three of which, I think could potentially be interesting to NDN.
这三者我认为可能对NDN都有潜在的兴趣。
So I just wanted to kind of put that out there to the group and,
所以我只是想把这个观点提出来给大家。
of course the answer any questions.
当然可以回答任何问题。
That's it. I think that's it for me.
那就这样吧。我想对我来说就到此为止了。
>> Okay. >> Kathy, I will pass it on the next.
>> 好的。 >> 凯西，接下来我会传递给别人。
>> Okay, great.
>> 好的，太好了。
Thank you, Dan.
谢谢你，丹。
We'll get back to probably with some questions.
我们可能会提出一些问题后再回复您。
Next I'd like to introduce Sokwoo Rhee and he's an entrepreneur and
接下来我想介绍Sokwoo Rhee，他是一位企业家并且是一位在物联网、智能城市和
executive with expertise in the internet of things, smart cities and
Next, I would like to introduce Sokwoo Rhee, he is an entrepreneur and an executive with expertise in the Internet of Things, smart cities, and wireless networks for commercial, industrial, and military applications.
wireless networks for commercial, industrial and military applications.
无线网络在商业、工业和军事应用中的应用。
He's one of the pioneers who have initiated and
他是最早发起和推动IoT行业自21世纪初期以来发展的先驱之一。
grown the IoT industry since the early 2,000's.
自21世纪初期以来，他促进了IoT行业的发展。
He is currently Associate Director for the cyber physical systems innovation
他目前是网络物理系统创新的副主任。
at the National Institute of Standards and Technology are hosting this.
国家标准技术研究院正在主办这个。
And he's been covering enough.
他已经报道得够多了。
Station programs for IoT and Smart Cities.
他负责物联网和智能城市的站点项目。
He manages the global city teams challenge, a US federal government
他管理着全球城市团队挑战赛，这是一个美国联邦政府的项目，旨在发展一个全球性的主要商业和技术利益相关者生态系统。
program to develop a global ecosystem of major business and technology stakeholders
旨在发展一个全球性的主要商业和技术利益相关者生态系统的项目
to create replicable and scalable IoT Smart City projects.
创建可复制和可扩展的物联网智能城市项目。
Prior to joining US government, he was co-founder and
在加入美国政府之前，他是联合创始人和
CTO of Millennial dot Net Inc.
在加入美国政府之前，他是联合创始人和千禧年点网公司的首席技术官。One of the first to successfully commercialize low
One of the first to successfully commercialize low
power wireless sensor networks and IoT technologies from Academia.
power wireless sensor networks and IoT technologies from Academia.
学术界的无线传感器网络和物联网技术的动力。
His work and achievements have been recognized in multiple boards including
他的工作和成就已经在多个领域得到了认可，包括
MIT technology reviews top innovators under 35 and he went to MIT.
他被《麻省理工科技评论》评为35岁以下顶尖创新者，而且他还曾就读于麻省理工学院。
And I would like to give him a chance to speak now, thank you.
我现在想给他一个机会发言，谢谢。
>> Thank you, Kathy, by the way,
>> 谢谢你，顺便说一句，Kathy，
I didn't expect you to read through my whole bio, that wasn't really intention.
我没想到你会把我的整个简介都读一遍，那真的不是我的本意。
And also, I am now much older than 35, that was a long time ago.
而且，我现在的年龄远超过35岁了，那是很久以前的事了。
So don't get me wrong for anyone, I don't look like 35.
所以不要误会，我看起来并不像35岁。
So I didn't even have to say it, so thank you for the intro.
所以我甚至不需要说出来，感谢你的介绍。
So I work on Smart City, I work on large scale IoT in general,
所以我从事智慧城市方面的工作，我通常负责大规模物联网项目。
but currently Smart Cities is my focus area.
但目前智慧城市是我的重点领域。
Now, I'd like to provide a little bit of perspectives on how sparsity and
现在，我想就稀疏性这个概念提供一些观点。
new networking technologies including edge computing,
包括边缘计算在内的新型网络技术，
can work together or may not work.
可以协同工作，也可能不行。
So there are a lot of buzz about edge computing these days.
如今，边缘计算领域有很多热议。
And then even in the Smart City area,
然后甚至在智慧城市领域，
a lot of people are talking about how to use edge computing concepts.
很多人都在讨论如何使用边缘计算概念。
In the context of a Smart City and in many cases,
在智慧城市的背景下，在许多情况下，
that what I see is technologies like me for companies.
我看到的是像我这样的技术为公司服务。
Basically, bringing this new concept and
基本上，是将这一新概念带入
try to push to the cities and the city officials, in many cases,
努力推动到城市和城市官员们，在很多情况下，
municipalities are perplex any cases, always gonna help me, right?
市政当局在很多情况下都感到困惑，你总是会帮助我，对吗？
So there's a huge gap between this the actual users, it was Smart City or the,
所以在这个实际用户之间存在着巨大的差距，那些是智慧城市的，或者说，~!@#$%^&*()
for lack of a better word, customers that was Smart City technologies.
所以用一个更合适的词来说，那些是智慧城市技术的用户。
And the suppliers, and that question is done new here,
而供应商们，这个问题在这里是新的，
it's been around for a long time.
它已经存在很长时间了。
But when it comes to new emerging technologies such as 5G or
但是当涉及到5G或者这样的新兴技术时，
edge computing, that problem is amplified much bigger.
边缘计算会将这个问题放大得多。
Because edge computing conceptually, the way that typically,
因为从概念上讲，边缘计算通常是这样的，
the companies explain that is,
公司解释说，这是因为~!@#$%^&*()
use that computing you can reduce the bandwidth requirement.
使用那种计算可以减少带宽需求。
And the companies make it a big deal, and then say, so
而且公司们把它当成一件大事，然后说，所以
you have to install edge computing capabilities in a city, and
你必须在一个城市安装边缘计算能力，然后
then city officials go, okay, why should I worry about it?
然后市政官员会说，好吧，我为什么要担心这个呢？
Only reason I should worry about is because I got to pay more for
我唯一应该担心的原因是因为我得为此付出更多的钱。
the cell network, cell bandwidth.
蜂窝网络，蜂窝带宽。
That's really, then question comes down to, okay, if I install this devices,
这真的很关键，那么问题归结为，好的，如果我安装了这些设备，
are you saying that I don't need to use cell network to get to the edge compute?
您是在说我不需要使用蜂窝网络就能连接到边缘计算吗？
So the last mile problem is still not solved,
所以最后一公里的问题依然没有得到解决，
because you cannot use WiFi because there's too
所以最后一公里的问题依然没有得到解决，因为你不能使用WiFi，因为信号太弱了，在整个城市环境中可能还好。
short in city environment in a whole environment, it may be okay.
所以在整个城市环境中可能还好。
But it gets down to broad Metropolitan environment,
但说到广阔的大都市环境，
you still cannot really avoid relying on a cell network,
你仍然无法真正避免依赖蜂窝网络，
even if your edge devices are built in.
即使你的边缘设备是内置的。
So the point I'm making is this, in Smart City area,
所以我想表达的观点是，在智慧城市领域，
edge computing is a 5G's buzzwords.
边缘计算是5G的热门词汇。
I think there is still time and there is a gap in adoption,
我认为仍然有时间，而且在采纳方面还存在差距。
especially, it's computing 5G.
尤其是在5G计算方面。
I think is gonna happen much quicker, because Apple no matter what, and
我认为这会发生得更快，因为无论如何，苹果公司……
frankly speaking, the carriers will not want to let us not have 5G.
坦白说，运营商是不会允许我们不使用5G的。
They wanna simply just keep manufacturing devices on 5G, replace it with
他们只是想继续生产支持5G的设备，用它来替代
the 4G device and we weren't enough, I have a lot of choice out there.
他们只是想继续生产支持5G的设备，用它来替代4G设备，而我们的选择并不多。
But when you come into the municipal network or municipalities,
但是当你进入市政网络或市政当局，
who are probably the bigger customer, that's a little bit different.
可能是更大的客户，这有点不同。
Because they may still, although, networks are still operating in 2G network.
因为他们可能仍然，尽管，网络仍在2G网络中运作。
A lot of people, many people, not many people know why, but
很多人，许多人，不是很多人知道为什么，但是
a lot of them are still running on 2G or even 3G networks.
很多人仍在使用2G甚至3G网络。
So point as for edge computing and NDN too,
所以对于边缘计算和NDN（命名数据网络）也是如此，
these kinda new concepts to wanna get into the mainstream.
这些有点新的概念想要进入主流。
I think we need to have a very clear pitch, and
我认为我们需要有一个非常明确而有说服力的陈述，
very clear and convincing message.
非常明确而有说服力的信息。
Why this new technologies we're gonna help municipalities to operate and
这些新技术将帮助市政机构运行并~!@#$%^&*()
deliver their services, and fulfill their mission.
这些新技术将帮助市政机构提供服务并完成它们的使命。
I'm gonna stop there for now.
我就先说到这里吧。
>> Okay, thank you, and thanks for introducing this idea that maybe
好的，谢谢你，也感谢你介绍了这个可能性。
we need to think about creating applications which have some pull
我们需要考虑创建一些具有吸引力的应用程序。
instead of trying to push them on people who might not want them.
所以我们可能不应该强推给那些可能不想要它们的人。
So maybe we're looking in the wrong places, so-
所以我们可能在错误的地方寻找，所以-
>> Wow, you summarized it, I spent 10
哇，你总结得真好，我花了10分钟讲了一大堆，你却用[笑声] [听不清]，太棒了。
minutes talking a lot, you summarized it in [LAUGH] [INAUDIBLE], awesome.
我花了很多时间讲了一大堆，你却用[笑声] [听不清]来总结，太棒了。
>> No, no, you are very good, thank you.
不，不，你做得很好，谢谢。
Next, I'd like to introduce Dr. Geng Wu and he's an Intel fellow and
接下来，我想介绍吴耿博士，他是英特尔的资深院士以及
a Chief Technologist for wireless technologies and standards.
他是无线技术和标准的首席技术官。
He leads Intel's 5G and 6G technology development and ecosystem collaboration.
他领导英特尔的5G和6G技术开发以及生态系统合作。
Okay, that's what comes after 5G, I guess,
好吧，我猜那就是5G之后的事情了。
he serves as the head of Intel's delegation to 3GPP.
他担任英特尔代表团团长，参与3GPP。
And he's a director of the board of the IOWN Global Forum,
他还是IOWN全球论坛的董事会成员。
the multi-fire alliance and the automotive edge computing consortium.
多火联盟和汽车边缘计算联盟。
So, boy, you've got your fingers and
So, boy, you've got your fingers and ~!@#$%^&*()
everything at the edge, go ahead, your turn.
一切都在边缘，继续，轮到你了。
>> Thank you very much, so it is my great honor to be here and
谢谢你，能来到这里对我来说是一个巨大的荣幸。
well, if there's no virus situation,
嗯，如果没有病毒情况的话，
we would be having a drink with the co-panelists after the session.
如果没有病毒情况的话，我们会在会议之后和其他小组成员一起喝一杯。Excited to be here, so let's me just
Excited to be here, so let's me just
兴奋地来到这里，所以让我简单地
say a few words about why I'm here.
兴奋地来到这里，所以让我简单地说几句关于我为什么会在这里。
So the topic that this particular session is addressing,
所以这个特别会议讨论的主题是，
it's actually very interesting.
它实际上非常有趣。
Internet of Things and edge,
物联网和边缘计算，
both are very much to the heart of the 5G industry.
它们都是5G行业的核心所在。
And also the next upgrade platform upgrade that in the next ten years,
并且在接下来的十年内，还有下一代平台升级。
we're working certainly on the next generation.
我们当然正在致力于下一代技术的研发。
So there's some fundamental technology drivers supposes,
所以有一些基础技术是假设的驱动因素，
for example, the need for network performance,
例如，对网络性能的需求，
as well as the localization of machine intelligence and
以及机器智能的本地化和
machine learning are really driving the networking and
机器学习确实在推动网络和~!@#$%^&*()
computing functions for the network edge.
机器学习确实在推动网络边缘的计算功能。
Having said so, there is also assumption,
已经这样说了，还有一个假设，
kind of in common between these two important,
这两个重要的事物之间有某种共同点，
probably the most important aspect of the technology development for
科技发展最重要的方面之一可能是
this and the next generation, which is that
这和下一代最重要的是，即
The solutions are well we do see,
我们确实看到了解决方案，
in both cases we have the fragmented the design and
在这两种情况下，我们都对设计进行了碎片化处理，
the solutions and so basically basically different optimizations.
在这两种情况下，我们都对设计进行了碎片化处理，解决方案本质上是不同的优化。并且我们经常看到的问题是……
And quite often we see the issues that
在这两种情况下，我们都对设计进行了碎片化处理，解决方案本质上是不同的优化。并且我们经常看到的问题是……，是的，这些解决方案难以扩展并且
yes, these solutions are hard to scale and
是的，这些解决方案难以扩展并且
some of the panelists the colleagues here already mentioned that.
一些与会的小组成员，这里的同事们已经提到过了。
So basically, how do we actually horizontalise the technology and
那么基本上，我们如何真正地将技术横向扩展，
more importantly the market at the industry?
更重要的是行业市场？
That's probably one of the key issues that we need to address.
这可能是我们需要解决的关键问题之一。
If you look deeper from a purely technology viewpoint,
如果你从纯粹的技术角度更深入地观察，
I think most of the issues really come in from the fact that we
我认为大多数问题实际上是因为我们
are dealing with a evolve the computing and
处理一个不断发展的计算和
networking and data model.
处理一个不断发展的计算和网络数据模型。
So that's a particular model actually, that drives the way we design the network,
所以这实际上是一个特定的模型，它驱动了我们设计网络的方式，
we did our platform.
我们搭建了我们的平台。
We did our applications as part of actually evolving.
我们将应用程序作为实际进化的一部分来进行开发。
To be more specific, for example, we do expect
为了更具体地说明，例如，我们确实期待
the next generation system to be platform to be at least order for
为了更具体地说明，例如，我们确实期待下一代系统作为平台至少要比我们今天拥有的快一个数量级。
magnitude faster than what we have today.
比我们今天拥有的快一个数量级。
We are seeing that the network,
我们正在看到网络，
the switching fabric for example, increasingly programmable even today,
例如，交换网络布局，如今甚至越来越可编程，
we can easily do one single part.
我们可以轻松完成单一部分。
This terabit is for multi terabits per second, fully programmable switching.
这个太比特是用于每秒多太比特的全可编程交换。
So that's not an issue.
所以那不是问题。
So there's it, that's a tremendous the technology opportunities there.
所以就是这样，那里有巨大的技术机遇。
We also see the challenges.
我们也看到了挑战。
We need to have a deeper understanding of
我们需要更深入地了解
the computer communication and
我们需要更深入地了解计算机通信和数据模型是什么意思以及
the data model, what that means and
数据模型是什么意思以及
how the NDN play a critical enabling role in this new word?
NDN在这个新世界中扮演了一个至关重要的启用角色。
Network obviously is no longer just a communication pipe that
显然，网络不再仅仅是一个通讯管道，它连接了两端。
connects the two ends.
连接了两端。
Is so tremendous your networking, computing and data processing.
你们的网络、计算和数据处理能力是如此巨大。
So those things are actually the cool thing is that NDN was
所以那些事实上很酷的是，NDN 是
actually very much designed from the very beginning to serve.
实际上从一开始就非常精心设计来服务。
To actually assume that the network is suggesting not just
实际上假设网络不仅仅是在暗示
a collection of communication pipes, so that's important.
一系列通信管道的集合，这很重要。
I think Dan touched on the fact that the zero
我认为丹提到了零信任是因为NDN的设计方式。
trust was because of the way NDN was designed.
我认为信任是因为NDN的设计方式。
That there are some unique capabilities,
这里有一些独特的能力，
that security capabilities that enable us to do something different,
这些安全能力让我们能够做一些不同的事情，
and those are the areas that we are looking forward to
和那些是我们期待的领域
work with the research community and to to address and
与研究界合作，解决并且
that's the reason why we are very much a strong supporter and
这就是我们为什么非常支持并且热衷于这项技术的原因。
passionate about the technology.
对这项技术充满热情。
Back to you, Nicole.
回到你这里，Nicole。
>> Okay, what I guess I should there's one question I have here this very
好的，我想我应该在这里有一个问题，这非常
specifically for Justin and let's do that and we'll see if any others come up and
专门针对贾斯汀，我们就这样做，然后我们看看是否还有其他问题会出现。
see what we can talk about what among ourselves.
我们看看我们之间能谈论些什么。
If we'd like to know how far along is the NDN plus block chain solution and
如果我们想知道NDN加区块链解决方案的进展有多远，以及
what aspects are furthest along development, prototype,s deployed, etc?
哪些方面的开发进展最快，例如已部署的原型等？
>> Yeah, so we finished we finished the minimum viable product and
是的，所以我们完成了最小可行产品并且
kind of proof of concept early last year.
已经在去年早些时候完成了一种概念验证。
So we've been continuing to develop that product, though, so that the original
因此，我们一直在继续开发该产品，以便原始的
genesis block was created over a year ago, almost a year and a half ago now.
创世区块在一年多前被创建，现在几乎一年半了。
And so now we're at the stage where we're actually deploying that in test beds,
所以现在我们处于一个阶段，即我们实际上正在测试环境中部署该系统。
like I said, so we're gonna be taking part of that application and
就像我说的，所以我们将会把那个应用程序的一部分
deploying it in our mobile edge compute platform.
部署在我们的移动边缘计算平台上。
And then we also have a separate standalone application that's primarily
然后我们还有一个独立的应用程序，它主要是
just gonna be used for localized payment processing.
仅将用于本地化支付处理。
And so, we're doing that.
因此，我们正在做这件事。
So where you can actually take and just install this on like a Raspberry Pi or
所以你实际上可以把它安装在像树莓派这样的设备上
whatever, right?
无论如何，对吧？
And then but the idea right is that you have everything localized your web server,
然后，但是这个想法，对吧？是你已经将你的网络服务器，
your APIs, everything's localized right?
你的API接口，一切都已本地化，对吧？
And eventually where we wanna get to with this is we wanna have the entire
最终我们想要达到的目标是我们想要拥有整个
front end application built with NDN, right?
前端应用是基于NDN构建的，对吗？
Built on top of NDN.
基于NDN之上构建的。
And so right now we're just using it as kind of like a middleware.
所以现在我们只是将其作为一种中间件来使用。
And we're just passing it through the satellite network and
所以我们只是通过卫星网络传输它，
or any other network that we're kinda using, right?
或者我们正在使用的任何其他网络，对吧？
But we're trying to prove out that we can use NDN across a satellite link here
但我们正在尝试证明我们可以在这里通过卫星链路使用NDN。
in the next couple of weeks with our block-chain application.
在接下来的几周内，我们将会应用我们的区块链应用程序。
And then I think the next steps for that right is that to kinda go
接下来我们要做的，我认为是继续前进。
back to kinda some of the things Dan brought up as well.
回到丹提到的一些事情上。
We're looking at that blockchain application in the mobile edge compute
我们正在研究移动边缘计算中的那个区块链应用。
platform for auditing, primarily, right?
主要是用于审计的平台，对吗？
Assurance is a big one.
保证是一个重要的方面。
On-boarding is another huge one.
引导新用户是另一个非常重要的方面。
So, we've got to be able to take that blockchain application and
我们必须能够将那个区块链应用程序进行调整，以便我们能够将其应用到那些类型的场景中，让它足够通用。
have it vanilla enough to where we can apply it to those types of scenarios.
我们必须让它足够通用，以至于我们能够将其应用到那些类型的场景中。
Or now we we can say, hey look, we can use zero knowledge proofs to validate
我们现在可以说，嘿，看，我们可以使用零知识证明来验证
that the identity of this user is who they say they are without exposing their entire
身份，同时不暴露他们的全部个人信息。
privacy, but also at the same time validating that the traffic and
隐私，同时也验证确保网络流量和
the data that's coming through the network is not volatile.
通过网络的数据不是易失性的。
It's not gonna cause problems.
它不会引起问题。
It's not gonna take the network down.
它不会导致网络瘫痪。
It doesn't have kinda some nasty payloads and some stuff in there as well.
它也没有包含一些恶意的负载和其他一些东西。
And that really speaks more to the military and
这实际上更多地体现了军事方面的情况，
government applications we're that seeing for requests for
政府应用程序我们正在看到的请求是为了
a verifiable trace routes, auditing assurance for whether you're
可验证的跟踪路由，无论您是否进行审计保证
spinning up applications or Kubernetes clusters or whatever that case might be.
部署应用程序或Kubernetes集群等，无论具体情况如何。
But All those RF
但是所有那些射频
kind of like spectrum analytics are gonna have to have auditing trails as well.
类似于频谱分析也将不得不有审计追踪。
The FCC is pushing for that.
美国联邦通信委员会正在推动这一举措。
So a lot of these different mandates that are coming down from not just governments,
因此，许多不同的规定不仅仅来自政府，还来自私营行业。
but also from private industry as well.
同时也来自私营行业。
And then also the the governing bodies like 3GPP and all these other things.
还有3GPP和其他各种管理机构。
So we're looking at that.
所以我们正在研究这个问题。
We're saying hey, you know, next steps for us is we really have to make
我们在说，嘿，你知道的，我们接下来真的必须要做的是
the blockchain application deployed on the mobile edge compute platform.
我们接下来真的必须要做的是将区块链应用部署在移动边缘计算平台上。And now we can really open it up to all those IoT based applications to
And now we can really open it up to all those IoT based applications to
start off with.
start off with.
从这里开始。
Now, because there's a huge developer pool out there that we're pulling in from
现在，因为外面有一个庞大的开发者群体，我们正在从那里吸引人才进来。
Nvidia and Intel and some others, right?
英伟达、英特尔以及其他一些公司，对吗？
So we're gonna be able to enable those applications to run at the edge.
所以我们将能够使这些应用程序能够在边缘运行。
And then that's gonna give us the ability to work with industry and regulating
然后这将使我们有能力与行业和监管机构合作。
bodies and everybody involved, to really make sure that we can go to the DOD and
机构和所有相关人员，确保我们能够前往国防部并且
say, Hey, here's an option for you if you want to deploy this on network.
嘿，如果你想在网络上部署这个，这里有一个选项可以给你。
To verify your routes, you can, are all the different analytics that you need or
为了验证你的路由，你可以使用所有你需要的不同分析工具。
zero proof knowledge kind of applications as well.
零知识证明类型的应用程序也是如此。
Thanks, Justin.
谢谢，贾斯汀。
There was a question that I think you already answered, Dan,
有一个问题我认为你已经回答了，丹，
that came up from Dave around about the traffic analysis.
那是戴夫提出的关于交通分析的问题。
But that brought up something for
但这引出了一些问题。
me that back when Van was first talking about what became NDN.
这是在Van最初谈论后来成为NDN的东西时的情况。
I was consulting to this Airforce thing called TMOS,
我曾为这个名为TMOS的空军项目提供咨询服务，
which was a satellite based network that was servicing all these military networks.
它是一个基于卫星的网络，为所有这些军事网络提供服务。
And the chief architect of that was really interested in this idea because of
他对这个想法非常感兴趣，因为
the somewhat counter-intuitive idea that he said, you can send traffic
他说的那个有点违反直觉的想法，你可以发送流量
in all different directions, not just where you want it to go.
向各个不同的方向，而不仅仅是你想要它去的地方。
So I guess it'd be like you sending pizzas all over DC or
所以我猜这就像你在华盛顿特区到处送披萨一样，或者
something [LAUGH] or sending pizzas every Friday.
所以我猜这就像你在华盛顿特区到处送披萨一样，或者每周五送披萨。
And I mean that's sort of, we think about efficiency.
而且我是说，这在某种程度上，我们考虑的是效率。
But I mean what do you think about that idea is that that's sort of
但我的意思是，你怎么看待这个观点，它在某种程度上是~!@#$%^&*()
the opposite of efficiency, but it's sort of obscuring what's really going on.
效率的反面，但这在某种程度上掩盖了真正发生的事情。
>> Yeah, I think that's a great example.
是的，我认为那是一个很好的例子。
I think there's a lot of interesting potential there where, and
我认为那里有很多有趣的潜力，其中，
back to sort of what I've always taken sort of as the NDN mantra is it's very
回到我一直认为的NDN口号，那就是它非常
hard to hide that volumetrics when it's a point to point circuit, right.
难以隐藏那种体积度量，当它是点对点电路时，对吧。
Cuz it's hard to say, but as you point out, right, we could
因为这很难说，但正如你所指出的，我们可以
with 5G there may be applications where I've got enough bandwidth and
有了5G，可能会有一些应用场景，我拥有足够的带宽，并且
I actually don't care if I'm burning some additional bandwidth.
实际上，我并不介意如果我消耗了一些额外的带宽。
So I don't care if I'm sending data in random directions.
所以我不介意如果我随机发送数据。
I like your example of I might just call up Domino's in Arlington,
我可能会随便打电话给阿灵顿的Domino's比萨店，
Virginia and send pizzas to 20 different directions and who knows.
弗吉尼亚州可能会向20个不同的方向发送比萨，谁知道呢。
So that's a real possibility.
所以这是一个真正的可能性。
And so
这样一来
we're trying to get away from that idea of being able to easily identify the source.
我们正试图摆脱那种能够轻易识别出来源的想法。
Another example that's come up is, yeah, I have all these devices,
另一个例子是，是的，我有这么多设备，
they could serve as relays, they could serve as.
它们可以作为中继器，它们可以作为。
I could talk to Kathy via anyone on this conference,
我可以通过这次会议上的任何人与Kathy交谈，
maybe via 20 of you on this conference, and then.
也许通过会议上的你们中的20个人，然后。
So it's interesting to see what you could hide if you put aside
所以，如果你把某些东西放到一边，看看你能隐藏什么，这会很有趣。
the goal of I don't have limited bandwidth, I have plenty of bandwidth.
所以我不是带宽有限，我有充足的带宽。
I don't have a small number of paths, I have plenty of paths.
我不是路径有限，我有充足的路径。
Does that give me some new advantages?
这是否给了我一些新的优势？
Maybe it does.
或许确实如此。
>> Done on mute.
>> 静音完成。
Sokwoo, it looks like you wanted to say something.
Sokwoo, 看起来你好像有话要说。
>> Yes, thank you.
是的，谢谢。
I want to say because this is fascinating idea.
我想说这是一个迷人的想法。
By the way, Dan, welcome back to federal government, by the way,
顺便说一句，丹，欢迎回到联邦政府，顺便说一句，
good to have you back.
欢迎回来。
So from DOD perspective, it may not be,
因此从国防部的角度来看，可能并非如此，
you may not need to be in the situation that you have a lot of bandwidth.
你可能不需要处于拥有大量带宽的情况。
You may have still limited bandwidth but
你可能仍然只有有限的带宽，但
you were willing to pay for it because it may be more secure in certain cases.
你愿意为此付费，因为在某些情况下它可能更安全。
It's like military is not always inexpensive,
军事并不总是便宜的，
the way you need the best and you need the most secure, most powerful.
你需要最好的，也需要最安全、最强大的。
So especially for DOD title applications, makes perfect sense.
所以尤其是对于国防部标题应用来说，这是完全合理的。
Well, you don't have to really think about efficiency as much as partial world.
嗯，你不必像部分世界那样真的非常考虑效率。
And probably you don't want to prioritize efficiency over other important factors.
你可能不想将效率置于其他重要因素之上。
So makes perfect sense, and actually just wanted, I mean this is intriguing you
这非常有道理，而且我只是想说，我的意思是这真的很有趣。
interpret that always [LAUGH] because we've been always thinking about this
这总是让人发笑，因为我们一直在思考这个问题。
we have to talk to talk about the security of the device or the manufacturer.
我们必须讨论设备或制造商的安全性。
That's why we're having all this discussions about, you know what.
这就是为什么我们会有所有这些关于，你知道的，那个话题的讨论。
But that's sort of like a whack a mole game.
但这有点像打地鼠游戏。
I mean, about validate one device is secure, but
我是说，关于验证一个设备是否安全，但这有点像打地鼠游戏。还可能有其他你可能无法验证为安全的制造商。
there may be other manufacturers that you may not be able to validate as secure.
可能还有其他你可能无法验证为安全的制造商。
So you cannot, and
所以你不能~!@#$%^&*()
this is sort of like an endless dilemma that you're gonna eventually face.
这有点像是一个你最终将不得不面对的无尽困境。
So probably the better approach,
所以可能更好的方法是，
Dan, as you mentioned is let's assume that everybody's insecure.
丹，正如你所提到的，我们假设每个人都不安全。
Let's assume all devices are insecure.
让我们假设所有设备都是不安全的。
Let's find a way still do our job on top of this
让我们找到一种方法在这个基础上继续完成我们的工作。
less secure, assumed less secure network.
较不安全的、假定为不安全的网络。
That's a fascinating approach.
这是一个引人入胜的方法。
That could solve, if you could come up with something really, really real,
这可能会有解决办法，如果你能找到一些真正非常非常真实的东西，
that could solve a lot of the dilemma that we have right now.
这可能会解决我们现在面临的很多困境。
>> Thank you.
>> 谢谢。
And a lot of this credit goes to my boss, Joe Evans, who Dr.
这份荣誉很大一部分要归功于我的老板，Joe Evans博士，他……
Joe Evans, who's put the big structure for the program in place.
Joe Evans博士为该项目构建了宏大的框架。
But I do think this is a, I do think there's a interesting way to
但我确实认为这是一个，我确实认为有一种有趣的方式来
think about this a little bit differently and to get out of the old mode.
我确实认为有一种有趣的方式来思考这个问题，打破旧有的模式。
And that's why I'm particularly interested in talking on this group,
正因为此，我特别有兴趣在这个小组里交流，
right, because I think it
正因为我这么认为，
also helps to have an architecture that's thinking along different lines.
也有助于拥有一种沿着不同思路构建的架构。
And it's a whole different matter to say how do I hide
要说我怎样才能隐藏这件事，那又是另外一回事了。
the fact that source A is talking to destination B, when I've kind of got rid
源头A与目的地B的交流事实，在我已经在很大程度上摒弃了源与目的地这一概念之后，我对内容的改变更多了。
of the idea of source and destination and I've changed more to content.
在摒弃了源与目的地这一概念之后，我对内容的改变更多了。
So yeah, so I think there's some real interesting potential.
所以是的，我认为这里面有一些真正有趣的潜力。
So hopefully, hopefully there'll be some fun stuff that comes out of this and
所以希望，希望这其中能产生一些有趣的东西。
we hope to get some interest.
我们希望能够获得一些兴趣。
But even if it's not for a DOD setting, and Sokwoo is exactly right,
但即使不是为了国防部的设置，Sokwoo 说得完全正确，
at a DOD setting they can pay for, security is worth the price there.
即使不是在国防部的环境中，他们也能支付得起，安全在那里是值得付出代价的。
So we can pay for some of those resources.
所以我们可以支付那些资源的费用。
But even in not a VOD setting, right,
但即使不是在点播（VOD）的环境中，对吧，
this idea of the added agility in the 5G network.
这个关于5G网络增加敏捷性的想法。
And can we take advantage of that?
我们能利用这一点吗？
And again, with this panel being focused on the edge,
而且再次强调，由于这个讨论小组专注于边缘计算，
a lot of that communication in those smart cities, in the vehicles, in the blockchain
很多在那些智能城市中的通信，在车辆中，在区块链上的通信，
authentication is really going to, can really happen substantially at the edges.
认证实际上会在边缘进行，真正大规模地发生。
And how does that work?
那是怎么运作的？
And it doesn't work well if I put it in a centralized model where it will all go
如果我把它放在一个集中式模型中，效果并不好，因为所有的东西都会去那里。
back to the, let's send it all back to the central server and let's do it.
回到中央服务器那边，我们把所有东西都发回去，然后执行它。
It works well in a distributed manner,
它在分布式方式下工作得很好，
which I think is well suited to do a lot of what the NDN communities.
它非常适合完成很多NDN社区的工作。
>> Do any of you have maybe just any particular
您中有人可能有任何特别的想法吗？
charges that you would say to the NDN research community?
您会对NDN研究社区说的看法是什么？
Things that you feel like would be particularly
您觉得特别会是什么？
good to look at that seem to be neglected areas?
那些似乎被忽视的领域值得好好研究吗？
Go back to that push versus pull model,
回到那个推力与拉力的模型，
what things would pull you in if you saw somebody working on that?
如果你看到有人在研究那个，会是什么东西吸引你？
It would make you kind of go, wow.
它会让你不禁惊叹。
That's a great thing.
这是一件很棒的事情。
>> I've got some.
>> 我有一些了。
>> Yeah. >> Wait, let's see.
>> 是的。>> 等等，我们看看。
Let's start with Geng Wu, he hasn't spoken for us yet.
我们先从庚午开始，他还没有为我们发言。
>> Okay, thank you.
>> 好的，谢谢。
So there's several things.
所以有好几件事情。
First of all, I would like to echo the and dance comments.
首先，我想要回应前面的评论，并且表示赞同。
In fact, even for commercial systems,
实际上，即便是对于商业系统来说，
the security is increasingly critical due to the nature of the network and
实际上，即便是对于商业系统来说，网络的性质也使得安全性变得越来越关键，
also the fact that the We are seeing the rapid
我们正在见证私人网络、企业网络等的迅速增长，这一事实也表明了
growth of private network, enterprise network and
私人网络、企业网络的增长以及
mission critical even from a commercial point of view.
任务至关重要，即使是从商业角度来看。
So, how to actually make
那么，实际上如何确保会话安全连接的洞察力？
the insight of secure the session security connection?
如何确保会话安全连接的洞察力？
How about directly security data snd how about protecting privacy?
如何直接保护数据安全以及如何保护隐私？
So those are the one of the things that really,
所以那些是真正重要的事情之一，
we need a research community is how to father and son.
我们需要一个研究社区，这是关于父与子的。
There are 2, there's a section for Nikko side to the question I said,
我们有两个部分，有一个是关于我提出的问题的日光方面。
What's the otherwise you have for the research community?
研究社区你还有什么其他建议吗？
I think there's 2 ways to look at it.
我认为可以从两个角度来看待这个问题。
One way is to understand
这个问题可以从一个角度来理解。
the opportunities that I think that Dan actually touched on that,
我认为丹实际上提到了那些机会，
the next generation we are going to upgrade dramatically
我们将要大幅升级的下一代技术
the network performance from device to network and to fabric.
设备到网络再到架构的网络性能。
So instead of trying to save every bit and then.
所以与其试图节省每一点然后再。
What would it be Indians technology potential,
印度的技术潜力会是什么样的，
because the way is doing things are dramatically different.
因为做事的方式截然不同。
What would the diet gave us assuming that you are running
假设你在跑步，饮食会给我们带来什么？
the next generation network.
下一代网络。
So that's the last aspect.
所以那是最后一个方面。
To be more specific.
要更具体一点。
The other aspect is the things that we were very much interested in.
另一个方面是我们非常感兴趣的事情。
Is to look at Indian as a tool as an opportunity
是将印第安语视为一种工具，一种机会。
for the network to go a status and professionalize.
为了让网络达到一种状态并且专业化。
There's this are 2 separate things but people often call the London together.
这是两个不同的事物，但人们经常一起称呼它们为伦敦。
Stay less means that since your service are more localized and
"Stay less"意味着由于你们的服务更加本地化，
you're going at the edge, etc, etc so and also we're going very high frequency band,
你们正在边缘领域进行探索等等，我们还在使用非常高的频段，
they have a millimeter wave, they have a terahertz coming up and
他们有毫米波，他们还将推出太赫兹波。
then the connectivity really is not always there.
那么连接性真的并不总是存在。
Is probably more opportunistic.
可能更多是出于机会主义。
And then the question is, what are the technology really to make that work?
那么问题来了，究竟是什么技术能够真正让它工作呢？
And so the night one devices need to go stay less and session, less.
And so the night one devices need to go stay less and session, less. ~!@#$%^&*()
Well, can you actually build the security around?
那么，你真的可以围绕周围建立安全措施吗？
More independent from the session itself inside of?
是否更独立于会话本身？
So there's many, many benefits.
所以有很多很多的好处。
I think that my co-panelists already addressed so I wouldn't, so, repeater.
我认为我的联席专家们已经解决了这个问题，所以我不会重复他们的话。
So I think, one thing we probably want to work on to the research
所以我认为，我们可能想要努力研究的一件事是
community to help us is to understand the new computing communication data model.
我们可能想要努力研究的一件事是社群如何帮助我们理解新的计算通讯数据模型。假设你拥有一个下一代平台，并且……
And assuming you have a next generation platform, and
~!@#$%^&*()
how you latter would make the MDN divinely help us to
如何让MDN神圣地帮助我们
build the next generation system and that benefit everyone.
构建下一代系统，使每个人都能受益。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
>> Yeah, thank you.
是的，谢谢你。
>> Does anybody else have something to add on that one?
>> 还有谁想在这个问题上补充点什么吗？
>> Yeah, let me go next, and then I know Justin wanna jump in too.
>> 嗯，让我接下来说，然后我知道贾斯汀也想加入。
But I talk a lot, Justin, just smile, I like your smile.
但我话很多，贾斯汀，只是微笑，我喜欢你的微笑。
And [LAUGH] so gain, I work on smart cities.
而且，我再次强调，我从事的是智能城市方面的工作。
So one of the biggest issues in our city especially from the perspective of data,
所以从数据的角度来看，我们城市面临的最大问题之一，
is this lack of interoperability even inside of the city operation.
所以这甚至是城市运营内部缺乏互操作性的问题。
So what I mean by that is that the transportation department may have their
所以我的意思是交通部门可能有他们自己的数据集和他们自己的通信与连接机制。
But the packets and
但数据包和~!@#$%^&*()
data are not necessarily packed in that there's no content.
数据并不一定是打包的，这并不意味着没有内容。
So typically if you use this communicate or
这通常意味着如果你使用这种沟通方式或者
system if just inside of department is okay because it's not from the when
如果只是部门内部的系统还好，因为它并不是来自于何时。
want to create a smart city system which is cutting across all different sectors?
想要创建一个横跨所有不同部门的智慧城市系统？
Suddenly it the data format, or the the packing of the data becomes a big issue.
突然间，数据的格式或数据打包成为了一个大问题。
So, I'm not necessarily getting down to the network layer or
所以，我并不一定要深入到网络层，或者
even below I'm not getting the data by more talking about application level.
所以，我并不一定要深入到网络层，甚至以下，我也没有通过更多的讨论应用层来获取数据。
But one of the biggest problems we are seeing is data packets,
但我们看到的最大问题之一是数据包，
which is typically the tag with IP address,
它通常是带有IP地址的标签，
some kind of address and the context over the content is completely separate.
它通常是某种地址，而内容的上下文则完全是独立的。
And that is causing a lot of problems in developing a more holistic,
这正导致在开发一个更全面的过程中出现了许多问题，
smart city data exchange network.
智慧城市数据交换网络。
So I'm not necessarily thing that is the problem and
所以我并不一定认为那是问题所在。
the network is going to be able to solve like a silver bullet.
网络将能够像银色子弹一样解决问题。
But point is, that's the problem I'm seeing from the Smart Cities perspective.
但问题是，从智能城市的角度来看，这正是我所看到的问题。
If there is anything that end in network can contribute.
如果网络能做出任何贡献的话。
Addressing it, perhaps bring that concept into data exchange platform that is
如果网络能做出任何贡献的话，可能是将这一概念引入数据交换平台，该平台正由众多不同的城市、州和政府共同开发。
being developed by so many different cities and states and governments.
正在由众多不同的城市、州和政府共同开发。
That could potentially change the game.
这可能会改变整个游戏规则。
I'm just throwing that out.
我只是随口一说。
That's right, Justin [LAUGH] >> Yeah,
That's right, Justin [笑声] >> 是的，
I'll be brief I totally agree with you guys and
我会简短地说，我完全同意你们的看法，
I think it's really important for us to focus on on the bigger picture.
我认为我们专注于更宏观的大局非常重要。
Whenever we're looking forward right and so anywhere we can we can pull those
无论何时我们在展望未来，因此我们可以在任何可能的地方采取行动。
levers and kind of improve things on a small scale or even on a big scale.
杠杆作用，可以在小范围甚至大范围上改善事物。
That's really where we should be focused.
这确实是我们应该关注的重点。
And I think for me, right, because I'm up in the weeds for the most part right now
对我来说，因为我现在大部分时间都在处理细节问题。
currently, but I think the forwarder is kind of our biggest challenge right now.
目前来看，我认为货代可能是我们现在面临的最大挑战。
And so if we could look at it, you know,
那么如果我们能看一下它，你知道的，
I think it was hit on some of the previous discussions where we can, you know, it.
我认为在之前的一些讨论中我们已经提到了这个，你知道的。
And the reason I say that is because if you look at how 5G works and
我之所以这么说是因为，如果你去了解一下5G是如何工作的，以及
dynamic slot you know just the slicing are long right and
动态时隙，你知道的，就是切片很长，对吧？
like we're looking at dynamic slicing, you've got a bunch of other things
我们在看动态切片时，还有很多其他的事情需要考虑。
that go into the like the the slicing aspects of it to right?
在讨论动态切片方面，我们还需要考虑到其他像这样的因素，对吧？
But moving forward into 5G and moving forward into those types of
但是随着我们进入5G时代，以及进入那些类型的
networks where you've got slicing and you've got CBR s in there too, right?
网络中包含了网络切片和CBR，对吧？
Where you've got different allocations for different uses.
你有不同的分配用于不同的用途。
So we're really, we're getting down to network utilization spectrum utilization,
所以我们真的在深入研究网络利用率、频谱利用率的问题。
but whenever you look at that from a forwarder standpoint.
但是当你从一个转发者的角度来看这个问题时。
Being able to create dynamic faces on the fly for thousands or millions of devices,
能够即时为成千上万的设备创建动态面孔，
or thousands of millions of users, and being able to do that and
或者成千上万的用户，能够做到这一点并且
update the entire network very rapidly and very quickly in like a 32nd time frame or
在短短32秒的时间框架内，非常迅速地更新整个网络，或者
less right for new policies and everything else.
在短短32秒的时间框架内，非常迅速地更新整个网络，或者对于新政策和其他一切来说，权限更小了。I think that's where our substantial challenges are at.
I think that's where our substantial challenges are at
我认为那是我们面临的主要挑战所在。
just with the Florida right now.
目前就在佛罗里达。
And looking at, you know, how do we solve that in the in the 5g challenge,
并且探讨我们如何在5G挑战中解决这个问题。
not just from an identity perspective, right?
不仅仅是从身份的角度来看，对吧？
Because this really comes back to fundamentally an identity
因为这确实从根本上回归到了身份问题上。
problem in my mind.
我脑海中的问题。
Right? And that is how do you identify the user?
对吧？那么问题是你如何识别用户？
How do you identify the node?
你如何识别节点？
How do you identify the traffic and so
How do you identify the traffic and so ~!@#$%^&*()
really saying If we have a trustful source, or a trustful destination,
如果我们有一个可靠的来源或一个可信的目的地，
right, it's everything in between that we have to fix to get it there and
对，我们需要解决中间的所有问题才能达到那个目标。
I think Indian is a huge leap forward to get you know, to get as 90% there.
我认为印度是一个巨大的飞跃，可以让你知道，达到90%的目标。
I think that there's just a little bit more we can do
我认为我们还能做得更多一点。
on the forwarder to really dial in the identity aspects.
在转发器上真正细化身份识别的方面。
And then create the faces dynamically as well.
并且同样动态地创建面孔。
Just,take that load off of developers.
只是，减轻开发者的负担。
>> Dan, you have anything you want to add?
>> 丹，你还有什么想补充的吗？
>> I think a lot of it's already been said I'll just add a quick thing in there
>> 我认为大部分内容已经有人说过了，我只简单补充一点。
that agree with all the comments there.
我同意那里的所有评论。
I think it's particularly interesting to see how does availability change and
我认为看到可用性如何变化特别有趣，
can I get a highly available network in a session less stateless environment and
在一个无会话无状态的环境中我能获得一个高可用的网络吗？还有
I think that gives me a lot of
我认为这给了我很多
new opportunities I couldn't have explored before.
新的机会，这是我以前无法探索的。
So I, I think, a lot of interesting directions to pursue here.
所以我认为，这里有很多有趣的方向可以追寻。
Okay, well, I don't see any other questions.
好的，那么，我没有看到其他的问题。
So I guess Dave had around had a follow up about
那么我猜Dave大概有一个后续问题。
wondering whether we were requiring that all the NBN routers be physically and
想知道我们是否要求所有的NBN路由器都要进行物理上和
logically secured but I don't think that I think that.
我不认为我们需要要求所有的NBN路由器都要进行物理上和逻辑上的安全保护，但我并不是这么认为。
As I heard several of you talk about it, it was more, you know, how do we work
当我听你们中的几位谈论这个问题时，更多的是，你知道的，我们如何工作。
in current environments, and that did not seem to be the requirement.
在当前的环境中，并不似乎是这样的要求。
But so anyway, I was thinking maybe we would just go ahead and wrap up and
但是无论如何，我在想或许我们应该继续进行并结束这件事。
I don't know if a lot peace on this we still take a half hour
我不知道是否为此我们还要再花半小时才能平息这件事。
break or less Somebody want to give us some guidance?
休息一下还是少一点？有人想给我们一些建议吗？
>> Yeah, I think we were supposed to come back at 3:15.
是的，我认为我们应该在3点15分回来。
So we'll take it 20 minutes and
那我们将休息20分钟然后
come back at 3:20 >> Great.
我们将在3点20分回来 >> 很好。
>> All right, it was very nice meeting you guys.
>> 好的，很高兴见到你们。
>> All right, see you guys later.
>> 好的，稍后见。
>> Nice meeting you.
>> 很高兴见到你。
>> Thank you very much to all the panelists.
>> 非常感谢所有的小组成员。
>> Thank you.
>> 谢谢。>> 谢谢。
>> Bye.
>> 再见。